The
first click,
I think I'm actually in though.
Can I?
Feels good.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Okay.
What you wanna put a little more, make sure it drops.
leah: Yeah.
Nice.
Okay.
We'll take gas on please.
Yes.
Low.
Okay.
Opening pressure six.
Perfect.
We can go.
Well, we're already on high flow.
We can get high flow or three.
I mean, even though the vari doesn't do anything limited by our instrument, we are insufflating.
leah: Okay.
Let's white balance our little guy.
Wait,
leah: what'd you say?
Oh, it's in the white balance
leah: Fail.
Usually you can white balance.
Are you where
all the monitors are?
Yeah.
Yeah, because I've got one right there.
Leah.
Is our light on?
So our camera
leah: on?
Is it on?
Nope.
leah: Nope.
Can we get the, um, the light on
looking at you?
I think right here you see where you can turn the light on.
Go down.
leah: I see.
And click your first one.
Oh.
leah: There isn't
it?
Beautiful
Turn back.
You can do that too.
leah: Thanks.
Okay.
I hate pressing all those damn buttons.
I just don't know why they just themselves over there.
Okay.
God damn.
So annoying.
Thanks.
So
now
big
leah: stick back there.
Rock.
Okay.
Just want somebody to just get it off this.
There we go.
Okay, here we go.
No, totally small things.
There is.
Yeah.
leah: I just find that camera navigation system annoying.
Okay.
Almost there.
One more.
I'll take the Optive view.
Yeah, she's up to 15, 14.
Thank you.
leah: He likes it.
How does he like it again?
No, I mean, just where he likes the, to see everything.
See if that's okay.
Take this out here.
Yeah.
Okay.
leah: Let him know if you need that down or anything.
Or if you're good, you may need to focus a hair.
Yeah.
Nice.
Lots of twisting.
brian: Okay.
leah: All right.
Nice.
You can drop your angle.
Yeah.
Perfect.
Okay.
Real quick.
Open up.
Perfect.
leah: All right.
Let's take a little pickaroo peek.
Actually clean this and then I'll take this, please.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you
two.
Thank you.
leah: Alright.
And just look straight down, check everything, make sure no injury.
Nice.
We didn't insulate any momentum.
Beautiful.
Yeah.
Check everything.
I love it.
Okay.
Or traits with the
leah: Yeah, it's fine.
Okay.
All right.
Given her, I was gonna do, um, super umbilical for our next port.
This will be another five.
Okay, this.
Thank you.
Not like a 15.
Okay.
A little bit bigger, the elevens.
It's okay.
Do you want an elevens?
No.
Totally fine.
Alrighty.
Okay, now, right now let's switch our camera here to the ambo port, and then we'll do our epigastric port.
That'll be our big one.
Yep.
leah: What do we have?
We have an 11 or 12.
Do you wanna go to the, and we're gonna go like, um, so I think that's to the right of the, our policy.
Yeah.
leah: I usually try to Google kind of through it.
And I feel like for this you can never be like, I mean you can, but you can never really be too high.
So I just think a little bit higher than you expect and then
come through and then angle through FCI towards gallbladder,
but kind of like coming.
Can I see the other side of fie real quick?
Just because I know.
Dr. George when we went in last time too, you said it kind of angled almost come like a gray.
Yeah, exactly.
Crot like, like the, almost like the crotch over the fsy hangs down.
So I'll take a, um, find your needle real quick.
leah: I feel like she's like catty
head,
so I think you're a little too low.
Okay.
Yeah.
So you wanna come up higher?
Okay.
But you wanna come through here and then angle through that side.
Yeah.
You might not be able to see it.
You might be going through FAU
brian: can remember, but I think you're going mark to the skin.
Remember, so you have landmarks for yourself.
Okay.
It's easier.
I'm too lateral.
It's just a, A small pearl.
Yeah, just wherever you mark it, it's okay.
But draw some landmarks for yourself.
This is xiphoid right here.
You wanting to be just a little bit up here and then almost like,
leah: so I actually don't think that's xiphoid, that's why I think you're off midline.
Xiphos here.
Yeah,
OIDs here.
We still want to go like medial to fallacy
leah: or Yeah.
I would go like, you could go like right here and then when you put your
port in, you'll come down and then you'll angle through fallacy that way.
Okay.
brian: Draw a big line, three hash marks on it.
Remember?
Yep.
brian: That'll be fine.
And then you use that as a reference when you're doing your needle there.
You'll know where you're at when make a decision.
Okay.
Something I'm like, it's weird 'cause I, there you're, yeah, this is kind of actually where I wanted to come out.
Like right there.
leah: Yeah.
Right on that side of f.
In what size is this port again?
This is gonna be, we're first gonna put in a five then no or no?
11. 11. Just, yeah.
I was just asking.
leah: 11 or 12.
Yeah.
Okay.
Sorry.
leah: No, you're good.
I was asking Fine.
brian: We should talk about skin incisions at some point.
Okay.
That massive hemorrhage is avoidable.
leah: Remind problem
and then, yeah, just watch.
So you don't Skype too much.
I usually try to come and, and then turn angle.
brian: Every angle you actually have a finder needle angle.
Remember Exactly with angle.
That wasn't the angle.
It was that way.
Yep.
And it was slightly all elevated up.
That was your angle.
Go from the finer needle.
If you do that, you'll come up where you want
it's
leah: noise.
Perfect.
Back and then we'll switch the gas to here.
leah: Alright, let's see.
Gallbladder.
There she is.
Okay.
All right.
Let's do our lateral track support.
This is one I, um, think a lot about.
Okay, Dr. George.
So I just wanna double check that I don't put this in the wrong spot.
So you'll look a little more, um, inferior.
Yep.
brian: Which one do you think lot about?
Um, I'm thinking about my lateral and my second, my hand part.
Yeah.
That second board's really critical.
'cause the operator, if it's too far away, their shoulder's painful.
There's a lot of considerations.
leah: Is that an okay spot for the lateral cord?
brian: Yeah.
We haven't done one of these before.
Huh?
This probably shouldn't.
Not a while.
One with you first.
Nonetheless.
Physically annoying, so, yeah.
Yeah.
So, uh, to you, I mean, not to me.
Sorry.
Oh, well it would probably not me too.
So, uh, what I'd like to do is grab the gallbladder and, and so you take gallbladder and
you have a knuckle of it and you'll go across, so your angle of that port needs to be so up.
'cause if your down too much, your, your ends are gonna be in the middle of the gallbladder.
This, this is a gallbladder.
Mm-hmm.
If the ends are in there and then you push up it perforates there.
Okay.
So you want it all the way across, which means it needs to be down low enough to do that.
So entirely depends on the anatomy of how tall the gallbladder is.
That looks like once you elevate, you'll be in an angle that's going up.
Mm-hmm.
And there looks fine.
If you need more room, you can go side, go upside down.
Right.
Would you
leah: go more down on the patient body wall?
So
brian: it's more inferior go the more you lose your angle actually.
Okay.
Alright.
So it's actually fine to be somewhat higher.
Okay.
leah: I'll take the needle please.
Take the knife please.
Hemorrhage.
Ah, okay.
Thank you.
Mine your way, cat.
All right.
We'll see if that's okay.
Okay.
Um, now we gotta do our other left hand port.
You have another, um, no, we can take, we can just use this one and I can just towel, we'll do a towel clip.
Okay.
So, Dr. George for this, um, left hand operating port,
my thought would be about here.
So it's not in the way.
brian: So
leah: it's relatively in line.
It's not blocking the camera.
The better
brian: is 'cause you can kind of move things around without hitting camera and hitting your other instrument.
Right.
Okay.
But the farther away you are, the worse it is on your left shoulder.
Right.
Because it's farther away from your axis.
leah: Okay.
brian: Um, so I actually will do one, one hand away from that one.
Right?
That's little.
Yeah.
So I would actually bias a little more.
You're gonna find it's gonna be quite painful to your arm, otherwise, okay.
The up and down piece is relevant also for your shoulder.
The higher you are, the more triangulation spread there is.
The more your arm's up like that, right?
The lower you are, the more you're relaxed
leah: and have it where you want it.
Okay.
brian: So it's all trade offs.
There's no right answer in this, but don't, that seems like a
reasonable experiment and then you're gonna feel how it feels to you.
Okay?
Okay.
Could make it painful.
Yeah, it might be, but I, that looks reasonable to me.
leah: Okay.
brian: You know, it's a little, little more I than I would go.
But you're young.
So, and strong.
leah: Am I strong?
I hope so.
brian: She's young and strong.
I don't know if you're strong.
leah: Yeah, me neither.
Big and strong.
He's the youngest and strongest.
I may the weakest link on the team.
I probably, I was gonna say you're older too with like,
brian: are you older?
Are you nontraditional student
research for a few years and then got a master's.
I was, alright, we're gonna
leah: move the gas.
brian: You went straight?
leah: No, I did a two year fellowship up in Boston.
Where?
Uh, research fellowship In Boston.
brian: Research book?
Yeah.
Is that in Boston?
As in like Harvard?
Uh, I was in Boston.
leah: I was like through the Brigham.
brian: Oh, fancy.
You can always tell someone from Harvard.
leah: That's not me.
I didn't tell them much.
Hello?
That's not me.
I was just, I'm joking.
Yeah.
brian: I thought Good.
Say again.
I thought it was a good job.
It's not that good.
Okay.
leah: Speed.
All right.
Ports are in.
Okay.
It's this, uh, prestige.
Prestige.
Perfect.
Thanks.
You mind coming in, Kat?
So
brian: there's, there's a, a weird technique that maybe do, once you
get exposure, I'll, I'll show you how it do you, we a little head up.
We do know what we did.
It was inflamed was the one we did.
Oh, sorry.
I didn't, please.
It's so you know how to do it then.
Do you remember how to get the knuckle
with like, that's good.
The heating of like the, um, where like cough, you ock get
brian: a little knuckle.
Knuckle.
Boom.
Remember that?
Yeah.
Kind of.
I know.
Yes.
I remember us doing it.
I don't know if I remember all the movements, but I remember like you talk, you got,
brian: can you get a hunter in your right hand?
Yep.
I'll, I'll help.
You can grab what you grab.
Oh, okay.
That's fine.
Cool.
She's gonna grab it and hand it back to you in a meaningful way.
That's not gonna be the real grab.
Okay.
Grab right next door.
Now.
Solid.
Right there.
Not too much.
Just a little.
And grab right there.
There.
Hard.
Now pull If you don't slip.
Okay, now you're gonna lift it up.
Let go of your hand.
Okay.
Now go underneath her all the way across.
Oh, yep.
Now I remember this.
The little baby bite and then the cross all the
brian: way across.
Crush it.
Good.
That's good enough.
leah: Okay.
I'm locked.
Lock it.
You can let it go.
brian: I hope you don't have, have fat in there.
I think you avoided it.
I think I avoided it.
I think I went about it.
I'm gonna let, let go.
Yep.
I'm locked.
Let's go.
And that's good.
And then that avoids putting your tips into the middle of a gall ladder.
Nice.
Yeah.
That's really nice.
Which especially it's inflamed is not a viable solution.
Yeah.
Okay.
leah: Okay.
Um, do you, diggen, do you mind taking the camera from Kat?
brian: I'm, you're gonna be happier if you go.
leah: And then once he does, you can grab another grasper.
Yeah.
Perfect.
The question's gonna be, did I really avoid that piece of fat right there?
Oh,
thank you.
And then can we get the room lights down please?
Absolutely.
Nice.
Thank you ladies.
You dig?
Okay.
leah: Then she'll take another grasper.
Do you want camera table down or do you wanna step
Um, I was gonna say table down.
And then actually, should we, before we, should we put her in, um, reverse trend down?
You want more head
leah: up?
Yeah, like more head up?
leah: Yeah.
Can we get more head up?
And then
leah: that's good.
And we'll get the table down a little bit.
leah: Then can we get table down just a bit and she'll tell you when to stop
demanding while we got everything positioned.
Yeah, we can get spots off.
Okay.
leah: Yeah.
Thank you.
Did you ladies need light?
leah: You good?
You're good.
Brent.
Up to her.
That's good.
And then we get a little bit more head up.
leah: We have a footboard, right?
Perfect.
Yep, we do good.
All right.
This'll be
good.
leah: Okay.
So let's make sure I got the fat out of that.
Not in my jaws, just gentle sweeps, sort of right where the top is.
And I would use both hands if you can and just kind of take both pieces down.
I would start, yeah, right up, right underneath my jaws.
If you can't get there, you can try to find another plane
and you can like grab a tiny piece of it and pull straight down.
Just don't push into it.
Yeah.
Nice.
And that
leah: looks nice and clear.
Um, I'm gonna fix your, you must have worked out this morning.
Your muscle I rip through.
leah: I would try, yeah.
I try to grab the really wispy right up at the top, so I'd let go and draw right up at the top.
Yeah.
Right there
with you.
Nice.
And when I came in the room I was like.
leah: Nice.
Okay.
And then you have to regrab with your left and come back at that area there.
Perfect.
Nice.
And if you can't, you can always like hook right through that clear stuff if you need to,
because that's clearly nice and clear.
leah: We just don't wanna rip.
If we have can't.
But you're doing great.
Show it to yourself.
Nice.
Yeah.
And you can hook that if you want to.
brian: Both this,
leah: yeah.
Stay
brian: right where you are.
So when you grab here, you want to rip there, right?
But it can rip anywhere between here and there.
That's what, yeah.
And it's gonna rip in the weakest spot.
The weakest spot is actually gonna be the fat.
Okay.
And what'll happen is you'll rip, the veins will break and it'll bleed and you won't be able to see anything.
So you want to grab as close to the plane as you can so you don't rip fat.
Okay.
Yeah, exactly.
You can use, you can always the other side of the plane too,
brian: right?
They're.
Yeah.
They need a little light to get a better view of what we're doing for the research project.
Okay.
So lemme
brian: troubleshoot.
Okay.
leah: It's easier.
You can hook that with your right hand
or not.
leah: Yeah.
I mean, if you can, if you wouldn't, because right there, if you grab
right on the edge of that lip rather than the fat, you would've had it.
So a smaller, smaller grab Yeah.
Of that portion.
Yeah, exactly.
Nice.
And you should be able to pull that down and you can use your right hand for tension against the gallbladder.
And
leah: if you wanna hook it, you're totally fine to hook it because I don't want you to rip the fat or anything.
You're good.
You're doing great.
leah: Yeah.
I'd grab right where that thing wants to rip.
Yeah, right.
Like right there.
Yeah.
Nice.
leah: I was just gonna go.
Yeah.
You can get your hook.
I would hook it.
What?
Yeah.
Nice.
Now you Yeah, you can heal that if you want to.
Perfect.
And then keep pulling with your left.
Nice.
Okay.
I'd re grab, um, up on gallbladder.
Oh, let's see.
leah: Just be careful with that grab.
You may wanna grab slightly more on that lip.
Yeah, right there.
Yeah.
Nice.
Oh yeah.
Be careful once it gets too much.
Okay.
Nice.
I wouldn't grab too low.
I keep working where you're working on that.
Perfect.
A little bit.
Yeah.
You see that plane right there towards posterior, actually this sky right here?
Yeah, right there.
So if you grab that super wispy white stuff.
Close to the gallbladder.
Yeah, right there.
Nice.
That's a nice clear.
You should be able to come down with, and you can pull out a hook if you need to, or you can just pull,
brian: is this, are you seeing reflection from the light?
leah: Me?
Uh, my view's still totally fine screen.
No, it's fine.
brian: You're not, 'cause it's should be bouncing down.
Mm-hmm.
But I wanna make sure it's not bouncing back to you.
No, it's fine.
Your image is okay.
And you can, um,
leah: if you wanna hook that you can or you can keep pulling down.
It's okay for now.
Yeah.
Well not
brian: Okay.
The surgery.
Yeah.
leah: Nice.
You wanna hook that?
If you need to totally fine.
Maybe come back for a sec day.
'cause she should find herself.
I just called you day.
Wow.
A little nickname.
Sorry.
If like, if you were like, Hey, that's not my name, please tell us.
Well, I made up
leah: a nickname of my own accord.
Yeah.
Where it's pulling, you have good tension right there.
You can come through that wispy with your hook.
I wouldn't, yeah.
I wouldn't necessarily heal if I didn't have to just poke through.
Yeah.
Which is fine,
but yeah.
Nice.
leah: Yeah.
And then come back through that hole.
Nice.
And then use your left hand a little bit more to give a better fan to keep that angle nice.
Yeah, exactly.
Okay.
Nice.
And
leah: now we're getting a little low.
Just fine.
I'd regrab with your left closer to that whisk.
Uh, I'll have, I can, I can say like who?
Nice.
And just make sure you really thin it out.
'cause I can't see through all that fat right now.
Yeah, you're good.
Maybe grab that other lip.
Yeah.
I
was thinking this other little wispy guy here might be a little,
leah: I grab, uh, maybe a little closer to gallbladder.
I think you're grabbing a little too low.
Yeah.
And I, yeah.
And then use your left to fan sort of lateral if you can.
Uh, lateral.
Yeah.
That way you're showing yourself that hole better and stay really thin.
Nice.
Now you have that hole.
leah: Perfect.
Nice.
Yeah, she's definitely had some chronic inflammation here.
Huh?
It's a little thick, but probably just fat.
I was just looking to see if anything was down.
Yeah, yeah, me too.
Before, can you come in a little bit?
Taken Nice.
leah: Yeah, that looks nice and clear.
Just show yourself
and use your left hand to keep pulling it lateral.
Yeah.
Nice.
See how you're showing it more with that.
Perfect.
Okay.
Just be careful healing down into that 'cause you're getting close to.
All right, well let me pull, do you mind coming back just a hair day again?
I wanna take a peek at what kind of, there we go.
Great.
Nice.
Then we'll come in and then Nice in the horizon hall a little bit.
Other way.
Uh, it'll be turning your hand and putting like, so
brian: this is to you?
Yeah.
You're gonna have to teach him.
Oh my bad.
How to do this.
leah: Sorry.
I was thinking about the, I know dissection.
This is the hard part.
I know.
Teaching to operate
brian: is the hardest thing done in my by far, so, so it's a lot of cognitive load.
Okay.
So you're gonna have to make sure my bad.
Pay attention to everything.
Right.
leah: Cool.
And keep grabbing.
Yeah.
Nice and high on gallbladder.
Where that
brian: pull that way.
Don't pull that way.
It's more likely to rip in the plane then and grab closer.
Yeah,
leah: and I, yeah, like he said, grab closer.
Yeah, the end plane pulls.
That's a really good point.
Dr. George.
brian: Your time's off by middle, so grab it.
So your right.
See that little lip there?
Fat.
That's where you wanna be grabbing.
I use a Maryland for this.
It's usually more precise, but it doesn't matter really.
Yeah, that's good.
Nice.
Good
grab.
I'm trying to think about how do I get my left hand in there to help me a little bit more?
You can,
brian: what?
What I do is I use my left hand strip and I use my right hand to grab if I want, if I have both.
Otherwise, just she's your right hand and you use your right hand against her.
Right hand.
Okay.
leah: Yeah, that's a really good lip grab right there.
Nice
brian: go.
leah: And then pull.
Yeah.
Nice and down.
I think you can get that lip again with your Right.
Nice.
Good job.
This may need to be a left hand lip grab.
Yeah,
right there.
Yeah, exactly.
leah: And then remember pulling in planes so it's a little more down than lateral.
Yeah, just right here.
Here.
Up there.
Above.
Right there.
brian: You can't see very well because There you go.
There you go.
Nice.
A little above that.
Like here?
Yeah.
brian: And then you can rip with impunity because you know where it's gonna rest.
Nice.
leah: And I'd swing back around digging if you can.
Your place playing dancing with her.
It's probably mild.
Generally
brian: speaking here.
This instrument, or this is for you, David?
The instruments you want to point?
Not on the top.
It's coming on top.
The instrument itself is blocking the view.
If it comes off to the side, they can see around.
Got it.
So right there, she can't see behind her tip.
Right.
So you're gonna move back and forth and rotate the camera to get these things in corners or sides.
Okay.
Let's
leah: see how low we are.
'cause I'm seeing
brian: it's, it takes practice.
leah: Yeah.
Okay.
Nice.
All right.
Lemme give you a better retraction now that we're pulled a bit.
Okay.
I think you can get that one.
Uh, super wispy lip down.
Yeah.
brian: This is really great.
Yes.
Nice job.
This is perfect.
For your learning.
leah: Oh yeah.
I don't just be careful Too much of that.
brian: And you're learning.
Yeah.
leah: Yeah.
This is huge.
Alright,
brian: sorry to again.
So you're pulling up so much, you're making it pad, oh, I'm making it worse.
See how it, it should unfold a little bit.
It doesn't always work.
Let's see.
And it's, this is hard though 'cause that left road is like, it's right in the way.
Creeping.
Yeah.
We still hang out.
brian: It really does.
Okay.
It's hard to see it as critical structure, so.
Exactly.
So if you can't see a structure, what can you do?
So we can think about's, two options.
Think about like camera angle or retraction.
Okay, sure.
Three options.
We can like get the, like see if we can like kind of push this out.
Good.
That's number two.
Yeah.
What's the third option?
Um, this is really important
brian: for laparoscopy.
Move the tissue.
It's like
brian: we do it all the time and I make that
like an additional retractor port for that does No,
brian: sorry.
Move the, move the thing you're operating on so you can move the
things around so you can change your angle of view, which he's doing.
Mm-hmm.
You can change the things around you blocking your view or you can change what you're operating on.
Okay.
And
brian: if you grab the gall port out of the FSA and you're looking around, you can move it to where you can see.
Nice.
leah: Okay.
So we'll get that left hand Good grab
like here kind of making sure though that we have like a good left.
leah: I don't know about that grab.
That's where I wanna work.
So there, yeah.
leah: Yeah, exactly.
brian: Little slip
grab you
and then pull Jeff
leah: Grab.
I think you're going to um, be folding the tissue.
A hair with that grab, which is like, this is my hardest thing.
I'm trying
to think of like going lateral like we talked about and kind of like rolling it into my instrument.
brian: Oh, you wanna go lateral?
So where are you held up?
Where you held up?
Where do you want to dissect her?
To dissect her?
leah: I wanna You have Q-tips open by any chance?
I wanna get this.
brian: She's gonna give you a Q-tip Oh wow.
At the screen with Cool.
leah: Okay.
If the liver over outta the way she exposed for her to be able to see.
I wanna get this down and I'm wanna dissect here.
So I was trying to figure out how do I grab this, pull away.
That's okay.
Let still make sure that this, I can access this guy and like these whiskeys right here, I'll try
leah: to grab around here.
I think that's a, that's gonna rip.
Yeah, that's too, uh, you need a lot of tissue so it
brian: has more integrity.
leah: Yeah, exactly.
So avoiding grabbing that and grabbing more on this side with.
More tissue.
brian: So what I'm starting to see is this is gonna be in Right, exactly.
I think we can, that's gonna be that turn.
Mm-hmm.
I talked about on this, on this model here.
And then this stuff, you're still looking for that.
I don't know where it is.
I don't fat over there.
Right.
But we'll see it.
Okay.
That's where probably you're end up doing that move where you pull it out and suck it in.
I'll, I bet you.
But she's gotta get gun grab to really make a point.
Right?
Yeah.
'cause you know this is gonna roll.
Right.
leah: Okay.
Now to get this down is our next step.
I feel like we could either, I don't know if you're a big kitten or
person versus just continuing to get, like, Marilyn, make a plane.
Hook it.
brian: Sure.
I, I am a, I'm fine kidding nurse, but I will usually don't use just Marilyn.
Okay.
I mean, it's not super in plain anything.
I usually use a sucker if it's bad enough.
Okay.
leah: And I think your left hand isn't helping you yet.
No.
Yeah.
I think we were just,
brian: you know, coach her.
Tell me what you want, not what you don't want.
leah: Okay.
brian: What do you want?
leah: I think I still want a bit more tissue.
If you can get it.
This is hard, Kat.
This is the hardest part, in my opinion.
Truly the problem is maybe I'm screwing you up.
Maybe I'm holding too hard.
Yeah, I'd grab right around there air.
brian: So I think it's too, the area you're making is you're not opening your grasper enough.
That's okay.
brian: And put it all the way up.
Push it all the way in.
Okay.
Right there.
Yeah, push it all the way in now grab now.
That's a good bite.
Nice.
Okay.
And then you can,
leah: um, palm if you, if you're able Yeah, definitely palm.
Yeah.
I made my thumb numb for six months when I didn't palm.
brian: Oh yeah.
That makes me so sad.
It was a,
leah: it was a me problem.
It.
Cool.
Um, I'm trying to think about Nice.
I think Deon, if you don't mind coming back for a hot sec just so I can orient myself.
Yeah.
Okay.
Nice.
Yeah.
See, I feel like I see that turn coming in there, so we're gonna have to clear off this area.
If you're able to thin out any of that tissue,
keeping that good pull with your left that you had, I think that, that
gallbladder, I still think we're zoomed in.
I hear too much.
Yeah,
leah: I agree.
There's such a bad glare.
Yeah.
Let's, let's clean it and just like chill for a hot sec. Okay.
Okay.
Because we gotta get that down.
And once we have that down, you'll be able to get a better pull and we'll get a better idea of our anatomy.
And then I know he likes to work sort of in that space right by the liver.
Mm-hmm.
First, yeah.
My glasses.
Is that what you're laughing at?
No, I'm not laughing
brian: at all.
I'm appreciating this moment.
This is wonderful.
Isn't this wonderful cat doing?
We're helping this patient first and foremost, which is great.
And second of all, you guys are learning.
You're working together.
leah: Cat's doing a great job.
brian: We're all learning, frankly.
It's great.
leah: Okay, so let's get re get that.
Good grab.
You had Kat.
brian: Oh, not too high.
Your camera angle should be between, generally between 10 and two o'clock.
Like where And you're, yeah.
Generally between 10 and two.
If you're on the left side over here looking here, it'll be 10.
If you're over here it'll be two.
Okay.
We'll go.
But you can definitely vary between, between two.
Feel free to Okay.
But you almost never should be looking straight off, unless you're simply looking at your abdominal wall.
leah: I feel like that's distorting our anatomy, but I think that you're still in step three.
Yeah.
I think the grab is just still gonna get that stuff done.
Okay.
I
brian: think there's more to go.
Okay.
But, and I think it's too high.
Is that what you say too?
Yeah.
Too
leah: high.
And I think that it's getting, um, twisted.
brian: It's hard to see.
Like can you, can you do us a favor and just move this liver outta the way for a second?
Let's just take a look.
Yeah.
What we got over there?
Okay.
And then can you grab right there?
Kind of, this is in pw.
You see it there?
Yeah.
Grab right in in.
Be grabbing some of that fat.
There's vessel arter, arteries there.
Arties there.
That ridge.
The ridge is there.
Artery almost certainly.
Push in.
No, no, no.
Come on.
That's it.
Now pull this way towards the hip.
It's hard.
You got it.
It's the hardest part of the truly seven year program.
You're good.
leah: I still struggle with the ground crushed.
brian: Yeah, you're not, you're not getting your, once you push in, push in and engage.
There you go.
Now grab it.
That's it.
Nice.
Okay, now let's look behind here.
Megan, you do at too nice.
Okay.
Okay, so I see gallbladder here still.
So it's gonna be down there, I think.
Which is hard.
Yeah's, that's just hard.
So I, but I see this here, so I'm gonna guess it's right there.
So, because you can't see back here, I would actually start just scoring right there to be honest.
You think so that Yeah.
I'm sorry I didn't ask you what you want to do that.
No, that's why I'm,
leah: that's totally fine.
I would love What are you thinking?
I think it's little too late.
No, that's fine.
I was gonna say, I think we could take this shitty tissue there, you that for sure.
And get that down percent that may give, give us a little more freedom.
brian: So that's good.
And I'm sorry I didn't say that explicitly.
I was wondering if we do that too, but if we're too low, we're doing stuff we don't need to do.
It's not useful.
I don't think we are.
I think that's stuff's actually very useful.
I think plane wanted come across this here.
Yeah, I think so too.
Okay.
Because I could see our gall water turning there.
Yeah, I that's what I'm
seeing too.
Yeah.
Okay, great.
In, in whatever order you wanna do, that's fine.
As long as we have the same mental model.
Yeah.
leah: Up to you Kat.
If you want to keep thinning with that versus if you wanna do like
layer by layer, getting through, through hook thinning and taking it.
Good technique.
I think layer like going.
Um, let's see.
Where if like taking a layer helps out.
Yes, I think
leah: so too.
I think that, um, it'll be better with the hook faster and, uh.
Nice.
leah: And then come in a bit digging.
Yeah.
And we're gonna get this schmutz here.
I feel like you have an anterior lip you can take.
Yeah, I'd come in on that side
leah: and that'd get this,
this guy.
So come in like this.
Yeah.
And I'd say about right there.
A little lower.
Yeah,
leah: just get your hook through, thin it out.
Make sure it's safe.
Make sure you have tension with your Oh, oh yeah.
You gotta regrab
brian: and then there's time management.
Yeah.
You have to do too, right?
'cause you're not gonna get through the case in, in a reasonable time at this velocity.
Just monitoring that.
As long as she's making progress.
My general policy keep going, but there's always a limit to it.
Okay.
leah: And keep that good tension that you had with your left hand 'cause that was showing it to you.
Um, out not, not up that way.
It's okay.
Sorry.
leah: Do you ever use a locking grasper on the gallbladder if it's not inflamed or No.
'cause it concussion.
brian: So it's interesting because I'm an a CS surgeon, it's very rare that we have a gall bladder that looks like this.
Yeah.
And any of the gall, go ahead, please.
Oh no, I was gonna
leah: say nice cat.
Yeah, that's where you need to get under is that lip right there.
Push, push, push.
Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle.
brian: Almost never.
'cause it's lacerating and inflamed tissues.
leah: Nice.
Okay.
Pull out and take it.
Great.
That's exactly what we're gonna keep doing is working through that schmutz there.
brian: Nice technique.
You know, I go, she knows this, who we talking?
Go into that and sweep up and down.
Yes.
Because that's actually dissecting it off of the ductal structure.
And you need to, so once you get into that plane sweep, if you're gonna use hook for d dissection, which I love to do,
I'm just Yeah,
leah: no,
you're okay.
Having a hard time.
There's nothing there.
leah: You're fine.
Gotta just keep yeah, keep with that left hand tension too, because that'll give you something to work against.
brian: She's not getting anything because there's nothing to get.
She's
leah: okay.
All right.
So we should switch what we're doing then.
Okay.
So now we can start, what Dr.
George was saying would be our decision to score.
Nice.
There.
Go.
Yeah.
That's a, that's
nice.
Are here almost.
I think so.
Let's look.
Careful.
So that's our careful, I wanna say because yeah, yeah.
You're doing it.
Looking at your looking where we were talking to.
Okay.
I think that's the, like ous coming down to that Arc Q.
So I'm almost seeing this right here.
Is that where you guys are seeing like that little lip there?
Yeah.
'
leah: cause that's where we're gonna want to get everything down.
So I would come right here.
brian: Okay.
So see if I stretch what I would go slightly slower.
Okay.
And the reason is, I see this, see this right here and then an inflection point, right?
Mm-hmm.
That little, like you can see this.
So if you imagine where base is, base is probably right there.
Mm-hmm.
Right now let's look over here.
Right.
I don't see a lot over there to help us.
That's gallbladder there.
Gallbladder there.
Don't know down there.
So I would be aiming here because I know that there's gallbladder there.
Right there.
I can see it.
Yep.
Move your thing.
Um, so there's gallbladder there.
I know.
I don't know what's there.
So I wouldn't head down into nothing.
I just scared.
Right.
So I'd head from there to there, which gives me right there, which is slightly lower than you guys.
Slightly lower.
So that's why.
Okay.
Got it.
leah: So I'd start right there.
Yeah, exactly.
brian: Right
there.
brian: That might be a no in there.
It's a weird spot for No, but it sure looks like that.
Kind of looks
leah: like a nerve right here.
Yep.
Sure.
Yeah.
Just get through peritoneum.
So you'll just, boop zoo going, keep going through, through it.
brian: There you go.
One more.
Oh, that's good.
Alright.
You're aiming for here?
Yep.
Not down there.
leah: Nice.
brian: Wiggle, pull
leah: noise and then get back in your hole.
brian: Yeah.
You aim aiming, see how you're aiming down.
Nice.
You fix it.
Seeing it, you, you, you angles this way needs to be like that.
Okay.
Because you're gonna go around the backside here.
leah: Nice.
brian: Sorry.
Senior Resident: Nice.
And make sure you thin it.
Do the little sweeping.
brian: The technique here is you turn it sideways, push in with the heel.
Okay.
Push in, dissect in, dissect in.
Don't turn it yet.
That's sharp.
There you go.
Push in.
Push in in the plane.
Okay.
leah: Nice.
And then turn it
brian: and now sweep again.
And if it rips, that's a good thing.
leah: Great.
Because you're looking over here.
Is that one?
Oh, it's 'cause I was pointing at things.
Okay.
Yeah,
brian: it's okay though.
Yeah.
I took the light off of it because I thought it was disruptive.
I feel like
this is super glar and I'm, I'm like a little nervous to like, you know what I mean?
I don't know Leah.
leah: No.
Yeah, you're good.
I think you have one more lip you can take right there.
I was thinking like this guy right here.
Exactly.
leah: Yeah.
Nice.
And just pull out.
Bless you.
Actually pretty good.
Yeah, it is.
I see your edge there, aren't we?
I think,
leah: yeah.
I think that's one more fat lip you can take right there.
Cat.
Getting your heel back in.
That nice, that hole.
Exactly.
Perfect.
Okay.
Do you want to, um, pull your gallbladder medial and take a peek
at what you're seeing on this side of that dissection plane?
Yeah.
Nice.
I think that, that you can come through that part right there.
This stuff, right?
Yeah.
That schmutz.
Staying in that same plane
brian: and saying high up on gallbladder.
Push through the heel.
Get some dissection.
Yeah, because you, you freebie here, you're gonna be there anyway.
Yeah, yeah.
Right there.
Yeah.
The base is here.
That's somewhere else.
Yeah.
leah: And push through.
Nice, nice.
Take it again.
Right there.
You can tell that that's sch You can see that it's nothing behind it.
Nice.
brian: I'll stop for a second.
Okay.
So look to the right a little more please.
So I'm imagining right there is base in that little blackness.
Okay.
I couldn't imagine.
But the reason it looks like fullness coming down.
We saw this here, like I think, I bet you there's nothing there.
I mean, there's liver there eventually, right?
That's the anatomy I'm seeing.
leah: I agree.
brian: It, it looks like to me.
leah: Yeah.
brian: But I'm not totally sure what's going on over here.
It looks,
leah: no, I don't wanna go over there.
I'm
brian: not sure yet.
No, I don't, I'm not saying avoid it.
I'm just, I don't clarity yet.
Right.
We're talking about speed before.
Exactly.
Clear.
Understanding the anatomy is super fast, right?
I mean, I slow down.
What?
I don't know.
leah: Okay.
You got it.
And just, if you're struggling, you can think about your left
hand and, and ask yourself, am I doing what I need with that?
Yeah.
I think that's where you want to wanna get in right through that smudge.
brian: So I want you to be aggressive.
Stop for a second.
It's gonna be uncomfortable for you.
It's okay.
Okay.
I want you to go into that plane that is all floppy there.
Yeah.
I want you to go in solidly and I want you to not pull back as you turn, but actually almost push in as you're turning.
Okay.
Try it out.
Nope.
Start sideways like this.
And then like that.
Like this, like this.
You're like that right now.
You wanna be like that on the hook.
Push in with the heel like you were doing.
You're just doing this way.
Go right there.
Push in.
Push in more.
Turn while you're pushing and it should pop through.
Okay.
That's it.
Now you can wiggle it through if you want, but that's how you keep it hooked.
Okay.
How it kept falling off of you.
'cause you were kind of like, like not quite like not in there, you know?
And then
leah: sort of pull as you take your move.
Nice.
Coming in this way again.
You actually go up.
Yeah.
brian: Yeah.
Nice.
Now you're talking.
Nice, nice, nice.
Good job.
leah: Yeah.
Nice.
Now you're just taking peritoneum.
Yeah, sorry
brian: about to get a liver.
Oh, okay.
leah: Alright.
I can see
right there.
leah: Sometimes we can you score peritoneum where we wanna just get our duct structures
if you want, if you want score, if it's given it to you, you can, whatever you want to do.
Yeah.
It's dealer choice.
I was thinking, I was thinking it's kind of giving us, if it is,
brian: take it.
Sweep sweep in that plane.
They're trying to sweep it off.
Nice.
Yeah.
I go with the.
There actually.
I know it's a, yeah, it's aggressive, but it's hard to get in heel there.
leah: Yeah.
And you can make pretty good progress with these scores.
brian: The risk though, for you, the risk is it's getting the liver,
it's super easy to go on the hook and it folds over and you hook behind.
This is gallbladder.
Mm-hmm.
You have CISO here, you think you're in this plane and it, it
folds over and you actually get a, a nub and a gall bladder.
Oh, gotcha.
So that's the risk of hooking.
leah: Just make, think about your uh, left hand too.
If you're struggling.
That's my usual thing.
If I'm struggling, I'll say, what is my left doing?
brian: Your left hand sabotaging you right now?
leah: Because I think you're almost pushing it in.
She's absolutely
brian: pushing in.
That crevice is her left hand.
Yeah.
Look the back digging with the camera.
See where your left hand is.
Yeah.
You wanna be pulling it.
See how you're making a hole there for yourself?
Oh, sorry, cat.
See that line?
That's your left hand.
Yeah.
leah: From the grab it, pull straight out right
brian: over and try and straighten it to this out more.
And it maybe just the wrong grab for you to get that corner
leah: and if it is, we can always work somewhere else and then come back
to that with the new, grab a little lower and I'll free that part up.
You know.
Cool.
I think I, yeah, you can regrab.
brian: Good job not slipping.
leah: Yeah.
Truly might be artery coming in on that, but Right in that I think is where artery is.
Okay.
I think artery's gonna be right in there.
Yeah.
I
brian: think we, I think it's hard to know for sure, but I think we saw it.
leah: Yeah.
Still tough.
Um, but I think you can maybe get one more move here and if it's not working, we can go somewhere else.
brian: The technique there was.
You know your left hand when you're on this backside.
Careful the liver.
Yeah.
Watch out.
Um, when your, um, left hand's in your own way.
Mm-hmm.
Your left hand.
That's the principle she used.
Okay.
leah: If it's in your way, let's go somewhere else then if it's not working.
So we started our dissection coming along here.
We know we wanna angle back towards the liver, so let's start doing that part of the dissection.
And we know arties somewhere in here, right?
So we'll save super, um, superficial layer by layer and show it.
And duct too is a posterior probably
brian: do need.
Yeah.
The heel only works when you're on that way on the backside.
That's a very specific technique to that.
Okay.
leah: And the thing I want to keep in mind is that we are twisting this fat a little.
So when we come across, we don't wanna dig.
So just stay in nice and superficial there.
brian: There you go.
That's your point.
Yeah.
Nice.
leah: And just show it nice and thin.
Yeah.
And see
brian: I want to, so you can see your tip there, right?
Yeah.
That's so meaningful.
It's beautiful.
Is
that enough photos to it to like take it or That's it.
brian: Yeah.
Yeah.
Totally.
What, why?
Sorry, I don't understand your question.
Like
I just wanted to make sure that I saw enough and that it wasn't thin.
It was thin enough.
I was there that like, 'cause you
brian: also were going in and felt it and it wasn't thick, right?
No, it was very thin.
So it's cool seeing it and feeling it.
leah: Yeah.
Get right.
Yeah.
That's a perfect plane right there.
Nice.
Good job.
That's
what I was saying is like, I felt like this.
Yeah, you had a little extra stuff
brian: but it was fine.
You like where she's headed?
leah: Um,
almost.
brian: You get
leah: nice.
Yeah, because I felt like before, like I said, I was just a little
leah: Alright.
And just think about how you're pulling, make sure your left is still helping you.
Nice.
That was a nice adjustment.
Coaching.
She does have a bunch of dilated ducks, which we're thinking about, but we're safe here right now.
brian: Very safe.
It just feels stressful, but it's actually safe if you don't just like to talk about it to make me feel
better.
I feel like this is where I want.
Yeah.
There you
brian: go.
Yeah.
Right there.
Better?
Yeah.
We both want you to be inferior.
Right there.
Perfect.
leah: Yeah.
Nice job, Kat.
brian: Yep.
All safe here.
You can see through it.
Even if there was a pad vein deep to you or some horrible thing you don't want to touch, you're safe here.
Especially when you sweep.
Yeah.
That's your faucet.
She's, that's the faucet.
It's right there.
See how it, everything's like the, all the surfaces are going into that point there.
That's it.
The base of the gallbladder is gonna be right here.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Because you can see the, yeah.
Yeah.
I can see it.
Yeah, yeah.
So she's almost, you get one more move and you're perfect.
Yeah.
leah: Nice.
brian: You know,
leah: sweep.
Sweep and just think about how you More aggressive.
Yeah.
Pull this more
brian: finger sweeps and sweep up.
Nice.
And make sure you see it.
This is definitely territory.
Yeah.
There you go.
leah: Use your left hand.
You're good.
It's okay.
Just watch your Bovie.
brian: Is that a purposeful move or accidental?
That was
accidental.
That was my fault.
brian: Luckily it was actually productive.
'cause you were kind of dissecting everything up.
leah: I think you have one more move going posterior.
Yeah.
brian: You can't see the tension on it.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, that's the, that's really good.
Maybe it takes more than one.
Yeah, maybe one more.
leah: Nice.
Yeah, perfect.
Right in that whole, and we'll just pull carefully so we don't whack the little off.
That's
brian: little thick, right?
But there's nothing there.
It doesn't move like it's anything.
So I would take it
be very careful.
brian: This last one I wanna think about.
That's, yeah, I think that's good.
I think we're good.
You can't go up but I think you're a little deep.
Yeah, that's how
brian: I know.
Just try and come in with the camera for her.
leah: Yeah.
There's that top lip where that's
what I
brian: was.
Yeah.
You gotta be deep that vessel once you get there.
Okay.
Exactly.
leah: And you can do that.
Good sweep and dissection here that you've been doing.
Yeah.
Nice.
brian: Yeah.
Maybe just take that whole thing.
I dunno.
Just don't go halfway across that vessel.
That's all I really care about.
If you're gonna go deep to it.
Yeah, that's good.
Don't pull hard when you're moving up because you'll it before.
It cooks.
Some good buzzes through.
It's good.
You pulled too hard.
Okay.
Get it rip before you problem,
leah: because
brian: that's really important part to be able to see.
Yeah, I wouldn't keep pushing into it just a little bit here.
Don't burn there again.
Where we're right here.
No on top of it
because that's.
leah: Okay.
Do you wanna come up this lip here?
Or we can keep working back there.
brian: What do you wanna do?
I almost feel like it's kind of coming up a little bit this way, but I wanna see how it, like with the, okay.
And if it's, I guess.
She's good.
leah: Yeah.
There we go.
Nice.
Give a good pull with that left.
brian: That's really good.
Yeah.
So principal here, you guys, both of you.
Mm-hmm.
So you know you don't wanna be burning when it's touching the
gallbladder 'cause you make a hole in the gallbladder, right?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
But you don't wanna pull super hard 'cause you want to coagulate vessels before they rip.
Yeah.
That's where I feel like I, so there's a tension.
Mm-hmm.
The way you reconcile that is you go in, you sweep, so you have auto
mobility to get it away from gallbladder without having to pull hard.
Mm-hmm.
brian: Okay.
So that's why I'm sweeping is I'm developing the plane so that I can
kind of pull just enough to get the hook off the gallbladder but no more.
Got it.
Nice.
Okay.
Like this kind of where we're sitting here.
brian: Sure.
That looks better.
Let's see if it cooks.
Yeah.
That looks better.
Right?
Yeah.
Nice.
It took about half second to come through and then, and it's really important with vessels, right?
Because you can't pull hard on those.
Yeah.
brian: Left hand.
Is your left helping you or hurting?
Yeah.
Figure out how to, with my left.
How to pull better
brian: out.
You may just be running out of it.
I think
leah: we're running out.
Yeah, if we're running out, let's come back down.
brian: Okay.
Next step.
So get this there if you don't mind.
So yeah, next step is actually not quite that.
Um, it's gonna be not, yeah, I would probably
leah: turn my, like that come underneath.
Come on This side of it.
This guy right here?
Yeah, but I, yeah, that's fine.
Slide it down.
leah: There may be node right around it or duct.
She has dilated ducts.
Get some.
brian: Weird thing though.
It almost looks like there's a plane here to move the way it moved.
Looks like a note or something like it.
Does it look like an So see how that moves independently of this?
When you touch it, touch it again.
See Yeah.
Move.
Right.
This doesn't move at all.
No.
So it suggests to me there's a plane there.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now just be careful 'cause now what you actually want to do though is you have a peritoneal covering here with leaflet.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
What you wanna do is actually grab that and just peel it back.
Yeah.
Perfect.
It's the most efficient way to just expose that space and then you're
gonna be left the fat structures and peritoneal on the other side.
leah: Perfect.
brian: Okay.
leah: Marilyn to pull or
brian: That's what I use.
Yeah.
'cause it's curved or right angle.
'cause you want to grab a broad base.
You don't want to grab a little bit of it Exactly right.
Because it'll rip.
Right.
And
leah: then, and then ka The thing to think about is Maryland, Marilyn.
Yeah.
Is how you're pulling.
'cause you're gonna pull in the direction of the tissue, like the plane.
And that way it should pull easy.
Just like if you were doing open surgery.
The same sort of tension principles.
brian: So guys, yeah.
Do this.
Let's have her do this.
And I don't wanna talk about time
and then we, because I remember we wanted to talk,
brian: clip it.
Um, so you can get a along one tie on that side of the plane.
One tie on another side of the plane.
Yeah.
Nice.
And then I remember we like
leah: wanted a little more like, like this so that you're like grabbing
like that, like that and pulling across a broad base of your instrument.
And then I remember having a little piece of, a little bit, almost like in the crotch, Dr. George, say
again, like you had almost a little bit of it going towards like the crotch of the Maryland a little bit.
brian: Uh, as much as you can get.
It doesn't matter where.
Yeah.
It's as big as you want because physics where it's dripping.
If it's plane, you keep going.
leah: If not, I see.
Don't, yeah.
That's a really productive one.
leah: Yeah, it was.
I was just
gonna be a little smaller.
Yeah.
Out.
leah: Sometimes when you gr grab just a little bit, you pull and it bleeds.
So if you can spread the tension out across more tissue, where
brian: did ripped, I dunno if you noticed it ripped in the fat out of the plane.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Grouping the fat, not the plane.
I'm trying to figure out if I wanna, because I wanna be in this.
Not yet.
No, not there yet.
The step here is
brian: take this peritoneal stuff down.
That's all you're doing.
You're all the way over to the fossa.
So
brian: this stuff here, then that's enough.
You don't need more there.
It's this stuff up here that you care about.
leah: Okay.
And you can pull your left hand at a slightly different angle to fix that.
Yeah.
Nice
to get this.
So we're going with this, this stuff right here?
Yeah.
leah: And you can, there looks to be a lip up here that I would try to grab.
brian: The reason I have Q-tips is I go to point and then I get my finger dirty and I gotta change my gloves.
I'll take a Q-tip.
leah: I am a pointer apparently.
That's
brian: why I do it.
Oh no.
For laparoscopy, it's way, way better.
Okay.
Yeah.
leah: Yeah, I should.
No, you're doing good.
Pulls
brian: well with this technology is you can look and, and I just, I think the future is, I'm gonna be able
this look where I'm looking and, and have it show on their screen and I wouldn't pull back there anymore.
So I think it's gonna happen.
Yeah.
So what I wanna do is I wanna get where AI will show you.
Yeah, yeah.
leah: Dr. George for, for this next step, um, we still have more, we
need to clean off here and we need to get our posterior cleaned off.
brian: I wouldn't worry about the posterior yet.
Not yet.
Okay.
And sometimes you don't have to worry about it at all.
So, so you see that's smooth here.
That's smooth.
See, it's rough all here.
Yeah.
It's
brian: the smooth, which is peritoneum and it needs to come down.
Okay.
The only thing I wanna point out to you see how it looks like there's a band here?
Yeah.
Why do you think there's a band holding, uh, the peritoneum up
Right here?
Yeah.
Um, 'cause of like the, um, 'cause I didn't go through like the per for it or
brian: why do you think there's a band holding the peritoneum up there?
Are you talking about structures in it?
I will you tell me why is this trung up?
Oh, because of the weight of the, um, anatomy's actually formed.
There's an artery under it.
Yeah.
brian: It's guaranteed.
It's holding everything up.
Ductal s you stretch your left hand out, it's just the artery like here and it goes dway.
Okay.
So there's an artery there, which is great.
You wanna expose it.
So if you grab the perone over the top of it, you'll actually start to see it.
Okay,
brian: cool.
Look right here.
Yeah.
You keep
brian: going there.
I want you up there.
Yeah, so like Right that, but uh, hard to do it that way, but you can try
trying to take a bigger bite.
Don't grab the artery.
Yeah, I know.
I'm trying to think about how, yeah, yeah.
And you just saw it.
It's pretty shitty, but I know I'm just little bigger about how to get at, how to hold it, but like,
brian: okay.
Don't get too aggressive.
Don't get greedy.
Get what you get and then stop and re recalibrate.
There you go.
That's it.
Now you're doing, so this is a really fast way to, to skeletonize ductal structures in the cystic triangle.
Okay.
There's a couple more techniques that help this too, but
a weak sauce.
There's a Please.
leah: I was gonna say, I think that there's a tension plane here you could pull, but.
Try it.
Pull on it or, yeah, right here.
That was a good problem.
Perfect.
brian: Okay.
There's another technique, kind of the roll technique for grabbing this technique.
You want this in your, in your thing, but you want to garage base.
So what you gonna do is you're gonna take your time, you're gonna push in and then push that way.
Actually it'll bring that up into your, into your instrument.
We're trying to get that numb in instrument.
That's it.
And then grab it.
Okay.
And I don't think your tips grabbing anything else.
And I'll try and rip down.
So not quite big enough.
So you're gonna have a little farther past to do that same move.
It's hard.
That's it.
That'll work.
Should work.
Yep.
Keep going.
It didn't, but we see an there.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
Okay, so now you got a little more.
What do you wanna do next, Leo?
leah: Um, well I think that this can come down here.
Agree.
Because when you pull it, I saw that.
So it's like, yeah, this grabbed here and pulled.
brian: Big bite of it.
Yeah.
Big bite of it.
It's all weak fat.
Your plane's right?
Nope.
You grabbed off plane one.
This is your plane this time.
Above the plane.
This time.
Below the plane.
That's your plane right there.
That's it.
leah: Nice.
Good job.
Ka
Like the plane is,
brian: that's your plane right
there.
So you wanna go above?
Yeah, but
brian: put your, set that time just above the plane
and push in
brian: and then grab.
That's it.
That's the move.
That's the most efficient way of dissecting a plane.
Oh, beautiful pool right there.
Nice.
leah: That's probably as much as it's gonna give you there.
Okay.
I'm
brian: still seeing gallbladder there.
I know, I, it's kind of weird, huh?
leah: I'm wondering if we could thin and come across the anterior to it.
Yeah.
brian: What the hell's going on?
I just still don't understand the anatomy.
Yeah.
So it feels weird because it looks like, I feel like I still see stuff going like right here.
Is that what you guys are talking?
Maybe?
Yeah, I think that might be
brian: gallbladder, but who knows?
It's weird.
Oh, okay.
I'm gonna ask you guys to switch.
I'm only gonna do it 'cause we were doing this for two hours now.
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh, and I don't think we need to be through the cystic di dissection hour though, actually.
Right.
For an easy one.
So hopefully you feel like you've gotten enough learning.
I got, yeah, I got good.
Okay.
Why Don you guys switch?
I'm not at all.
I promise.
Today was very great.
Thank you.
brian: Yeah.
And some that was Rich.
Can't learn everything in one session.
No.
While you guys are switching.
So yeah, this hasn't touched anything yet.
Nope.
Okay.
I was good about it.
Just wanna make sure I set down
leah: again.
Here's this little guy.
brian: Thanks.
Good job.
leah: Yeah, you did really far.
Very good tip.
Are good technical learning for you?
I had really good coaching.
leah: Oh,
brian: sweet.
Really good.
It's all these little minutes.
Thank you.
You know that you, when you're learning mind if I get a
leah: step over here
brian: continue.
Exactly.
leah: Exactly.
Yeah.
Okay.
My, that's interesting.
Yeah.
I think that that very weird.
It's gotta be, I think
brian: that's in particular.
Yeah.
I'm gonna regrab just 'cause it has a double arc. One on these side.
You know what's going on with this, but I
feel like I learned a lot.
Thank you guys.
There we go.
It's
brian: important for your future patients.
Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, I see.
So I think you're gonna, yeah, generally speaking, I find it y at this phase.
Thank you.
Okay.
Honestly, because the reason is you want to put the cystic duct on scratch.
Oh, my bad.
leah: Yeah, I agree.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna tint with my right and then regrab it, my left.
Thank you.
You came in before you kind of like came in, rolled it, and then moved
it on the in field before when we were doing the other, um, lady talking.
Yeah.
Is this kind of where you were talking about where you pushed it in and you rolled it and we pushed a little
leah: back, uh, with the, your hand cat.
brian: We, right now we we're gonna grab below the artery, typically.
leah: Will you come in dig?
Yep.
Just trying to see exactly where I wanna grab, I think lower.
Yeah, yeah,
brian: yeah, exactly.
See what that gives you.
Then we push a, a hair more cat on.
Yeah.
leah: Are you not able to push back more with your Yeah.
Okay.
Is that okay?
leah: Yeah.
Yeah.
I'm not super convinced by that.
Let's,
brian: so Ken, your job is to push the edge.
That's how you know you pushed it up.
Yeah.
It's not ripping off and you elevated all the cystic stuff out of the.
The fsa, but not so much.
The liver folded over.
Nice.
So you're gonna experiment with those three variables, you to see which one is best for her.
leah: Let's take a peek exactly what we think is going on.
What do we think?
It's hard to tell actually.
Super hard to tell.
Oops, sticky.
I just wanna make sure we're thinking correctly about where her infundibulum is good, because she has dilated ducts.
So I don't wanna get, you know, confused and go too low.
Here's our sulcus of per se.
Above that, I mean, maybe I'll take some of this.
I don't know if we need to, but if we take some of this down.
What do you think, Dr. George?
brian: So I would actually, uh, I pull everything out so I can see.
leah: Now it's like, is this node
brian: sure, maybe I don't know.
Or is this, I don't know.
I don't know.
So where it's safe.
So where is it?
Safe?
leah: Well, safe technically is higher and posterior.
We that those are safe.
brian: Yeah, there's, there's several Parents are safe shortly.
You can go there if you wanted it.
Or you can go medially this, this fat, you know, you could start to bring that fat down too.
Okay.
That's gonna be safe.
As long as you're careful, right?
You don't want, this is not where you aggressively engaged and
instrument can really see what goes and then feel around in there.
Feel free to fill the doc.
And we don't know our base is, no I don't.
So we think our pops to either their note or it or it's a Right, right.
But if it's, if it's, it's in the base is gonna be there.
So I wouldn't spread up there.
'cause that could be dull.
leah: I think it might be.
Yeah.
brian: So this is nice fast cat here.
We saw the artery earlier.
Where was that?
That white right there.
That's a safe spot.
Use the landmark.
You come just medial.
Just lateral.
See if it gives it to you.
leah: Okay.
Maybe like.
In here.
brian: Sure.
Try it up.
If it gets it to you, it feels Looks pretty empty.
It does it.
You push in and it goes in.
Yeah.
That's a freebie.
You're gonna get all the way through on that.
I bet you
leah: just trying to make sure feels okay and make
brian: sure we don't see any white.
You wanna look in that hole with, there you go.
Good job.
Yep.
Now it feels like nothing.
Burger, right?
It does.
Feels like absolutely nothing because you're past the dock.
All right, push in, engage, push in, engage.
That's it.
Now,
push in hard, not engage.
That's it.
leah: Okay.
So we're technically through.
If you know
brian: a safe spot, just go for it.
That's speed.
Make sure you keep her.
Yeah.
But you know the anatomy move faster.
Focus.
Okay.
Now you're red ductus.
Yeah.
Or something.
Theoretically
leah: anterior to me.
Okay.
A safe spot here.
I'm gonna do one more.
Good.
Spread.
Engage.
We don't think we're too low.
We don't know.
Okay.
It's safe here.
All right.
brian: You don't know where base, I don't know,
leah: but I feel like I can come here.
I
brian: that too.
Good.
That's exactly where I would've gone.
Pushing a lot harder.
There you go.
Because you know what the anatomy is, right?
Yeah.
It's no need to be tentative there typically.
Good.
I love the bend on that.
Nice job.
Really, really good.
So she's bringing it up, she's doing that to stay close to dock again is one of the 10,000 things.
Right.
She's demonstrated multiple
leah: really fast.
Okay.
And if you're able to swing around and pop on this side, we'll see it on through.
Yeah.
Nice.
Thanks, Degan.
Okay.
That was great.
Now you know our base.
I can take that.
Yep.
You can
brian: see in there there's base.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Now we're, again, now we're covered with gas.
Right?
Okay.
We're talking about speed before.
All
leah: right, well, I'm gonna, I, I was gonna get my hook and take some of this down.
Sure.
Go for it.
Cool.
brian: Could be a, a artery coming through there.
Remember?
leah: Could be
all Perfect.
Thank you.
brian: Yeah, that's not an artery, right?
Just move like an.
leah: Nice and thin.
Okay.
brian: Yeah.
Do it.
It's not our, don't pull so hard though, because there's true
fat, fat vessels.
leah: Okay.
I'm not making moves by doing this.
Let's think.
brian: You should be thinking, where would I go next?
Always.
Oh, not you, her.
leah: I was like, I am.
brian: I know you are.
Okay, because you have to go next.
No, I'm thinking
like that was what I was thinking earlier is putting her stuff in there because that was
clear and almost like you could see if you could get a lip in there that off big sweep,
brian: aggressive sweep all the way up and down.
Even rips.
It's okay.
Big sweep.
'cause that's gonna be where we clip, so we need length there.
Okay.
Right.
leah: That, that's actually very helpful to think about the big sweep.
Yeah.
Even more sweep up even more.
It's
brian: fat all the way up.
Can you dissect it up more?
You know, if not, we can't.
Okay, great.
How?
Get to the, here
brian: we go.
Big sweep here too.
Strip that off, that duct.
That's it.
That's the move.
And then don't pull so hard when you're doing it because you, sorry,
that was my thought was continue cleaning some of that off.
Working through what she's working through right now.
Okay,
brian: now you, so it's a test, right?
I just broke answers that are correct.
But I, you should always be thinking, what would I do next?
And when she does that next and it works, you're like, okay.
And
brian: if
what you
brian: want to do next, she never does.
You should wonder why
big sweeps there.
So you see edge of duct right now?
I do saw, right?
Yeah.
You're brief.
That I'm staying away for.
So you're almost in the wrong place to do your dissection.
Ah, okay.
You know what I mean?
Because you're gonna, if you cut this, you have less tissue there to do your sweet width.
leah: Oh.
So I should not plan.
So just come out.
Okay.
You
brian: go into the right plane now you know where it's go right next to it.
Get a lot of tissue there.
Still not getting enough.
That's better.
That's okay.
It is what it's, and sweep up it out aggressively very aggressively.
Even more aggressive.
Rip it go, don't you?
I'm ripping.
leah: Okay.
Okay.
Yeah.
And then clear off.
leah: See, I'm
missed it.
I know.
I'm trying to get in there.
Yeah.
That was a good move.
Noting I see my plane there.
Okay.
Yeah.
Too much digging.
Oh, I see it right there.
Right there.
Hanging out.
Yeah.
Totally.
Okay,
brian: so there's, keep going.
I'm just gonna talk.
Okay.
So, uh, there's some risk in this.
Yep.
Because we're going in, we're picking things out and we can't really see on this side.
On the medial side, you can see really well and I, these moves pick me easier here.
I do them, but they're a little riskier.
Right.
I really like keep doing what you're doing, actually.
Stay there.
Okay.
I really like scoring on this side though, because I do too.
It releases it.
I can pull it out farther and I, I'm coming through fat.
I can do nothing.
There's no perine blocking, you know, so I, you know,
it has to be cut regardless.
So
you left hand in your own way
leah: a little bit.
So I was thinking about it, but it's currently fine.
Get one or you get one more
brian: give up.
That's really nice though, right?
We're starting to see base over there now.
Okay.
I see
leah: my duct coming in nice and clean.
I think I can still clean the duct.
brian: Really doing well here.
leah: I think I can still clean behind my duct.
brian: Yeah, you can't, but what?
It's up to you.
But remember how we got started at this?
Mm-hmm.
We were, we pulled this down.
You're like, where do we go?
Right.
We knew one thing.
What did we know artery was.
Mm-hmm.
We use that as our starting point.
leah: Okay.
brian: Okay.
You still know where artery is?
Mm-hmm.
And you can use the same principle now to take your Maryland on the other side of it.
You know exact words.
You can feel it.
It's very solid.
You can feel your way just lateral to that.
Okay.
With, I mean, appropriate caution, right.
Because there could be things coming across.
Right.
Okay.
But you know, there's something there that you can skeletonize.
leah: We come back a sec. Dig again?
Yep.
You're good.
There she is.
Okay.
Thank you.
And now we come back in.
Sweet.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Your art arties right
brian: here.
Sure.
So you feel your way.
I actually start on it actually, and I, and then roll off of it.
Yeah, that's what I do.
Okay,
because you'll be fast.
Turn
leah: to gauge.
That feels like absolutely nothing.
brian: Your technique's off you beating on for technique.
Yes.
So do it again.
Okay.
I want you to watch this time.
What happened?
You're upper time.
Do it again.
Shoot.
Don't change the data.
You changed something.
Did I?
You changed the thing you needed to change.
You rotated it down.
Maybe I just thought about it more.
When you rotate it up, you're just pushing down it and this one doesn't engage.
Okay.
You're not dissecting, so you rotated down there.
Both engaged.
You press them both in, there's friction.
Got it.
And bam, you're ready?
Yeah.
So your angle is when you see it fly like that, it's okay.
Just adjust.
Okay.
But you did it three times without adjusting.
leah: Leah, come on.
brian: It's okay.
But then when I asked you, you subconsciously adjusted.
It's ruined my teaching point.
leah: Everyone still saw the flailing, so,
brian: so I don't know.
It's bleeding.
Maybe fat, maybe known through free for you.
Right.
So, but there could be something.
Yeah,
see where you're on the other side.
Just because I'm, see if you can switch over.
There you go.
No left hand.
Maybe my ankles off yourself.
leah: No, I can't.
I think maybe eye angles off of that.
I go little harder.
brian: I dunno.
I think you're good.
leah: You think so?
brian: Yeah, sure isn't nice.
Well look at base on a second.
This is interesting.
So I don't, it almost looks like it's there, but then it looks white here and we dissect it over there.
So I don't know what's, I actually don't know.
That sure looks like base though.
leah: But this also looks like gallbladder.
brian: It sure does.
That's a very odd, so that just means slow down so we don't understand anatomy, right?
Yeah.
So anyway, you're down here.
You could be lower than we think.
Yeah, I agree.
Right.
That being said, I think you're okay to go through there and get it out.
Get up the other side.
Okay.
Maybe I'll come up higher or you can start higher, slightly higher, more, you know, whatever.
Just don't get a gall.
That's.
That's a handrail that, can you just say it again?
Your time, dammit.
Just flopped.
I dunno if you noticed.
I did
see how much more solid that is.
leah: Yeah.
brian: You were talking about speed wasted.
Moves are slow.
When I.
leah: One more and then I'll take a peek
push.
Alright, one more.
Nice.
Thanks.
Degan.
Yep.
leah: Good.
I like the slightly box.
That was smart.
brian: Up that way because then you can see it.
I think so too.
Yeah.
Pass down
there.
Now I would turn
brian: my tips up.
Okay.
A little.
No, no, go in.
It's dynamic.
You go in, you turn your tips up because this surface is actually like at that angle, if your angle here, you sky.
Oh, there they are.
leah: See 'em.
brian: That's come through.
leah: Okay.
It's not
brian: working for you though.
Um, aggressive.
leah: I actually feel like I'm making a move there.
It's just doing a thousand little spreads, but I could probably be more aggressive,
brian: just not seeing you when I should.
If it's fat, you know?
It should be easy.
It's good.
There you go.
Finally found it.
Saw your time.
I did.
They're,
leah: yeah.
brian: Okay.
Big spread the fat, big spread.
Okay.
leah: All right.
Behind artery, opening up our plane.
brian: Critical view here, huh?
leah: Great.
All right.
Nice big spread behind artery.
We've got the U behind the duct.
We can get some of the schmutz between ducted and artery if we need to.
The question is, do we think we need to, and then we gotta get our cystic plate
spread again here, because that's where we're gonna staple.
Yep.
Nice.
Okay.
I think we have a good window here.
How do you feel about getting our, that what you wanna do?
It's gonna come around the back of gallbladder to get our cystic plate.
brian: Cool.
Yeah, there's lots of things you could do here.
Well what would you do?
Uh, well would I do?
Well you gotta clear off the base, right?
Yeah.
So, and you've gotta skeletonize the ducks.
Those are two things you have to do, right?
So you've got a lot of fat there and you're not skeletonized, so,
leah: okay.
brian: You know how you get to the fat, it's probably easier on the medial side than the lateral 'cause you can see it.
leah: Yeah.
brian: I give you very high level goals.
If you want more detail, I'm happy to go to, I wanted to help
some stress.
leah: That's a bad grab.
Lip there.
Cake.
Maybe I'll hook across that.
Okay.
Yeah.
leah: It's gonna bleed
brian: with that dumb grab.
Grab camera please.
Coming with the camera.
Anytime she's dissecting.
You wanna be closed?
I'm gonna stop that.
She's coming in and outta the body or pauses to get a look around.
Come back.
leah: Okay.
I've gotta clean off my artery.
Gotta skeletonize my artery.
Do you usually just, yeah, I'll just pull,
get in there.
Difficult.
Not gonna do that.
Hmm.
brian: So that's your nodal
leah: bleeding.
brian: Okay.
So that's your node.
Yep.
So I would control, its va, its vascular, pedicle
actually.
Okay.
brian: And take it out.
It's usually the easy, it's usually faster to do that than let it bleed.
Have bleeding.
Okay.
So there's the upper pole and there's the lower.
Usually I go upper, but here you almost have, I have lower, dissect it out.
Yeah.
So I would dissect that out further.
Get behind it.
I go into, you know, and I'm coming this angle.
Sure.
brian: And just don't pull too hard because you want to coagulate this.
It's too hard.
That was
leah: still too hard.
Yeah, because it,
brian: it should take like half a second to go through there.
There you go.
That's there.
Yep.
Perfect.
And it stay on artery.
'cause you know, everything, this side of the artery is either nothing or a pedicle to the head.
Right.
Okay.
So push in with the heel mm-hmm.
And show you when to go.
Yep.
You know, a little bit of this.
Turn it, get a pick.
Make sure it's a pick on a big structure.
Slide up and down aggressively.
Okay, good.
Now don't pull too hard.
Perfect.
Okay, perfect.
Better?
Good.
Now you gotta be careful with this, right?
Yep.
There could be something in there that's mine.
So you're force these things, but once you get it, then you can slide up another breath, things it should be done.
Feels like nothing.
Doesn't feel like nothing.
leah: Feels like nothing.
brian: Little thick.
Okay.
Perfectly done.
leah: Perfectly done.
I still see my art.
I already got that.
Okay.
brian: Right.
Kind of got it.
Yeah.
Run.
You might just consider grabbing it, I dunno.
leah: The node.
brian: Yeah.
You can also try and go above it.
It should be, I don't know where it's vascularized.
Usually it's sized interior.
Right.
leah: Just trying to clean up my artery.
Sure you have to.
Yeah.
Which I could do.
Still bleeding.
Made it bleed again, didn't I?
Okay,
brian: good.
Pick it back.
It holding you open.
It's free.
Yeah, that's a good one.
You wanna the fat?
Mm-hmm.
Cook in.
leah: Okay.
brian: Now what
leah: I am trying to skeletonize my artery right now is what I'm trying to do.
That's my goal of my current steps.
Thanks Dagan.
Mm-hmm.
So I'm just gonna feel around behind it.
Sorry.
Okay.
I don't wanna dig into gallbladder, but I'm below artery.
brian: Lovely.
Pushing up artery.
That correct?
leah: Right.
Perfect.
Like I could be making more progress if I were doing something slightly different
appropriately when you weren't.
I'm just pulling on it
leah: slightly on here.
Why'd you go so low?
Why it go there?
Oh,
brian: why'd you?
You went up and that side down here, but you don't know what's down there.
True.
Okay, so it could be like hepatic arteries there.
Okay.
Let it go where you can see the tips.
There you go.
Now stay on that duck and spread wide
wide.
That's it.
Now you got a good job, right?
Yeah.
This thing's kind in your way.
I would just grab it, right?
The node.
Yeah.
There you go.
It up.
Up.
You took the Pele, right?
Theoretically.
leah: Theoretically.
brian: Because you gotta skeletonize the artery.
No, here's this,
leah: there's just dropped off node.
Okay.
All right.
So I need to skeletonize my,
brian: we dunno where the gallbladder is.
I don't know.
Into gallbladder.
Pretty that stuff.
Safe?
leah: Yeah, sure.
This is where we had made our previous, um, window.
The question is, do we have enough room to get our stapler around here?
I don't know.
I don't either.
I could clean this schmitz here.
That's gauge.
I'm just sort of hugging, engaging.
Yeah, I did.
There you go.
Much better
relative.
brian: Tilt it up other direction.
You til the wrong direction.
Your time tilted up.
Oh my time.
Not that much.
Go into that same hole.
Spread progressively a little more, you know, make some more progress.
Here.
Go, go, go.
That's it.
leah: Okay.
Right.
brian: I find it on this side easier to flip your finger out, actually.
Oh.
Because it curves around and get more distance on the fat.
Okay.
I don't know why I'm making the fat bleed so much here.
brian: I think that's totally safe.
Gentle that she wasn't sure where it was gonna rip in the plane.
So she was looking as she ripped and it didn't really what she wanted so she stopped.
Yeah, it didn't,
leah: I would maybe take some of this with my Marilyn in and out and then take my hook.
But
brian: lot of approaches here.
leah: Yeah,
brian: lot of tactics.
Familiar with the camera
that myself.
There is a lot of shit going on.
Yeah, there is.
Feels too.
I agree with how strategy I like it.
Trying to really push onto it when you do it.
That is
okay.
Don't
leah: love weird.
Oh then I made my artery bleed here
brian: so my, yeah, well that was my node but it wasn't totally vascular.
I, sorry.
Oh well
leah: that was my fault.
We're not vascular it.
Okay.
Sorry.
Do we want one?
brian: There's two poors
yet we can do is try and skeletonize that artery
my fault.
I'm sorry.
I want it out of there 'cause it needs to get out there.
But I, we shouldn't have a couple more burns around it.
leah: Okay,
brian: so I want you to dissect the rest of the artery out.
Okay.
Um, on both sides.
Use the Maryland, okay?
I'm giving you more tactical stuff right now because I think we should get that artery out of our way.
It's totally in the way.
Yeah, I agree.
That's, I want you to, what you do is I want you to go in there and hold on up, down on that spread, spread, spread.
Once you know how far it goes up, you're not at base.
Then come from this side.
Spread.
Get it fully skeletonized clip, click cut.
Okay.
Okay, great.
There.
brian: There too.
That's really easy.
Okay, keep going.
Really good.
So there's a little hanger up there or something?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Maybe coming off.
Mm-hmm.
It's okay.
Go in where you were.
That's good.
That was productive.
Just on a whole, that thing.
Okay.
Want cut it?
That's it.
Yeah,
leah: exactly.
Change my times.
That's it.
Perfect.
That slight move was perfect because that is, I think you're on VLA actually.
brian: You think so?
That right?
I dunno, because when you were lifting up, I only saw a VLA behind.
Yeah.
It's come from this side just down there.
Clip it there, you know.
Clear that off.
Good.
That was a nice move.
My grandparents, do you have 10 millimeter cup PLI out?
Yeah, you can open it for us, please.
Okay,
brian: that's great.
So we know that's artery, that's not emphatic.
That's not a duct.
Right?
It's too small.
leah: It's too small going directly into gallbladder.
brian: Yeah, it's fine.
So we're gonna take it Okay.
Little hour, because it's gonna hopefully help everything else.
Yeah.
And it's bleeding into the right.
So we'll do
leah: clip here, clip here, clip there.
Cut.
Okay.
Yeah, that'd be really nice.
Once that's out of the way.
brian: Yeah.
And then you're just start spreading through this.
Okay.
Cutting and spreading and cutting and spreading.
leah: Okay.
Thank you.
Thanks Kat.
brian: How does she know what angle that was?
We're trying to think about being able to see like the tips of the other like
brian: angle.
You turn the tips that way or do you turn that way?
I want
like kind of go in and then see like we could with right there Dr. George.
Sure.
Like thinking about the angle of like wanting to be around it but then seeing like,
brian: Nope.
So the core principle is this.
You have a duct or an artery or whatever.
You don't wanna go obliquely across perpen.
That's what I meant.
Yeah.
Like looking it up, perpendicular there, but then like making sure the tips there is that
brian: either way you see the tips.
Tips have nothing to do with what angle's.
Okay.
The angle is entirely about what makes it per the axis of the structure.
So sometimes the structure's that way you're gonna have to have curling down like that.
Okay.
Structure like that you're gonna have have report fixed.
You only degrees of freedom port.
Mm-hmm Left hand and with the angle of your, that's it.
Oh, okay.
So you're using both of those.
You can change the angle this way and you can change the angle with your Oh, okay.
Okay.
See how she's perfect.
Perpendicular these two were are not close enough together?
Yes, please.
Sorry.
Thank you.
leah: I should have done them, the bottom two.
Closer together, but not perfect.
It's not perfect, which makes me sad.
Totally acceptable.
leah: I was watching.
Oh, I know.
I saw, I was watching.
Me watching.
So now that we have that, then it'll be easier to clear off like this.
Ooh, I'm actually gonna just
leah: get my Beauvoir wa
okay
brian: to, are you guys okay if I take all El paa?
Yeah, a hundred percent.
In terms of like balancing service and education,
leah: I don't wanna go digging through this fact that I, it's, I agree.
I would've
brian: know exactly what you did every single part of Put it in, think it's thick, come out, try something else.
leah: I just don't wanna go in gallbladder either, but I think that's just peritoneum.
brian: I think what I would do is, yeah, you can try that, but if
you're not finding any targets for hookups, switch instruments.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Just, I, I would've, this is the perfectly acceptable effect and you learn.
Mm-hmm.
It's not useful.
leah: Okay.
Perfect.
Thank you.
brian: Your left hand's pretty weak sauce too.
Still.
Well, yeah, because you're putting this on tension, but you're not putting any of this on tension.
leah: Oh, okay.
Oh, see?
Yeah.
brian: Which is good if you're dissecting here, but it's not, not dissect.
That's.
Right.
She's gonna roll it to bring it on over.
Open times.
Grab right there.
Okay.
Oh, I see now.
Yep.
Now I see the roll.
leah: If I can do it nice and wide, I know I'm not gonna get a good grip here I don't think.
Fine.
brian: Your left your right hand.
It's not helping.
It's not.
No, we have to have cat show you.
There we go.
She actually mastered it.
I think that's better.
You still don't think that's better's susceptible?
Okay.
It's not as good as Cat did it the other day.
I'm not
leah: surprised.
brian: I know I'm, she did a really nice job.
Okay,
I have very good.
brian: And now you can see why it's useful, right?
Yeah.
I wanna say up on gallbladder.
Yeah, I think that's gall.
I think so too.
Just the way it moves.
It looks like I wouldn't go there.
Oh, I think that's gall there.
Okay.
This is not, I'm not sure yet.
Rip that.
Yeah.
brian: Okay.
So just the way it moved, when it pushed in there, it felt, and I wonder if
there's another, it looked like it kind of moved everything when you pushed.
Just try again.
leah: I dunno.
I don't know.
I think there's ball
brian: wire
leah: there.
You a posterior, I pull
brian: this here.
Okay.
That one feels freebie.
Mm-hmm.
Just see what you got in there.
You feel like that?
Yep.
Okay.
As long as it feels like that you're good.
leah: Just don't wanna hit a posterior artery.
Yeah.
What I would do is I often spread this way
brian: honestly, because I'm, I'm like making bands, but then I can cut later.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
leah: It's like this.
brian: Yeah.
Just feel your.
Dylan for gallbladder.
Yeah, I'm trying to
leah: push up.
I think that's gallbladder there, so I'm trying to push up against it.
That was a nice one.
Try to get posterior plane and I saw a white bear, so I did.
Oh yeah.
'
brian: cause you don't know what's gonna be there.
So then come back.
Oh, that was really nice, by the way.
Now you have a band for your hook later.
So go slightly off now and do the same exact route.
Okay?
Yes.
Perfect.
Okay.
leah: Making the bleed Classic.
brian: Now.
You got some targets though.
leah: Okay.
brian: I think there may be an artery back there.
Yeah, I agree.
Where it's common or hepatic, I guess.
I don't know what's going on here.
That's a little bit of a Gotta be careful.
It's big too.
I think
leah: Schmutz right here is, I think this right here is sch sch.
That might be
brian: a hepatic duct.
This, not this.
Oh, okay.
I was like, I think this is not bad.
leah: I wouldn't been making lot more noise.
Okay.
Yeah, that's interesting.
All right.
Yep.
Just pushing up against what I think is the base of gallbladder.
brian: Yep.
As long as it doesn't curl in front of your tips, you're good.
Yes.
So you gotta be really careful.
leah: Okay.
Keep
brian: going though.
If you're gonna do it, do it.
leah: Yep.
brian: Nice.
I love that you pulled down.
That was
leah: great.
That was nothing.
Okay, great.
Yeah, that was great.
brian: That was really nice.
Set of, that section was okay.
Yeah.
Really advanced.
leah: Okay, great.
Okay.
All right.
I'm gonna take those bands and see what we see after we take those bands.
Whoa.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Yeah.
I'm not gonna go deep.
Nice.
But we had a little plane here.
brian: Oh, that looked awesome.
leah: Okay.
Just seeing what we have.
brian: Totally.
Yeah.
I love that.
Next section that we're doing.
There's, there's something under there.
Something that for sure.
There's something real over there.
I agree.
leah: I'm just feeling.
Okay.
How about this?
Not bad.
I think that's just bad.
brian: Okay.
leah: But I'm still wiggling.
brian: Yeah.
Makes me feel reassured.
A little more.
A little more mobility there.
leah: Yeah.
There's my tip.
brian: Okay, good.
leah: Let's see what we have there.
What's
brian: going on here?
This is kind of weird.
Weird.
Okay.
leah: All right.
brian: Let's
leah: take a
brian: peek.
Make, see small things and slow down.
Kind of like when we were like a little bit in our gallbladder, we're like, let's slow down.
brian: Mm-hmm.
Fast.
And Australia is slow on the curve, right?
That is, I dunno what that is.
Liver might be, liver.
Could just be liver
leah: that feels like Pierce nim.
I'm just gonna see.
Hmm.
I wonder if I'm through
brian: Yeah, that's what I wonder too.
That's my hypothesis right now.
Times missing.
brian: Left hand is key there.
They're push it a little more there.
They're without
leah: hitting.
Okay.
So I feel a little bit better.
Yeah.
We
brian: were just looking through a little bit of band para.
Yeah, I think so too.
leah: So I'm gonna spread there.
What you guys think too.
Yeah.
I, I was gonna spread here and continue to open up that plate,
brian: that move blind on liver capsule.
I'll tell you some experience can cause a lot of bleeding.
Ah, okay.
I don't wanna do that.
I've done it.
I've done it there that you can see it.
That's, yeah.
Much better spread aggressively.
It doesn't matter.
Right.
But you don't want to do.
Without seeing it.
leah: Nice.
Thanks Dagan.
Good driving.
brian: Really good driving actually.
Yeah, you're doing great.
Far, far above average.
Uh, a plus.
I'm gonna give you an a plus for the rotation.
Okay.
I appreciate that's how you guys great, right?
I honestly have no idea.
We go, it's not a plus.
I can show you.
It's a vague system of honors and high honors.
leah: Okay, great.
I feel better about that now.
Okay.
Question is, is do we think this is anything?
brian: Yep.
That is the question.
So, yep.
Pass some courage, but be cautious.
That's it.
Why'd you start so high?
leah: Because I thought I saw a liver bed in a band there, so, okay.
I mean gallbladder.
brian: So I see this band here.
Mm-hmm.
I don't know what it is.
It's either base, gallbladder or it's some of other weird structure and you started above it and went across it, so.
Oh, gotcha.
I would be like, not the place I go.
Okay.
I would've gone just below it and see and then I would maybe work on that.
You know?
leah: So maybe like here,
come right below it.
Yeah.
I see.
Thank you.
brian: Very productive.
Very fast, Leo.
See how fast that was?
'cause you knew we didn't have this
like med school green felt a little bit like line, is it anyway, where the points are made up and don't matter.
I think that's
leah: just fat right here.
Yep.
brian: You can rip it with a little bit bleed.
You can pause and cut.
Dealer's choice.
I feel like I wanna rip it, but it's all about consequence of bleeding.
That's not a high consequence area.
No.
Well shoot exposure there is pretty good over here.
On the other hand, I don't just rip things and have righting down everything.
Right,
leah: right, right.
Okay.
leah: All right.
What about that one?
I think that's Schmitz.
Yeah.
brian: Feel it.
But it looked like Schmitz before.
Feel it when you're good.
And then while you have hooking, see what else you can do.
Put it behind.
That's nothing.
Burger.
leah: What?
That shaky hand had my cell.
Huh?
brian: Explore some shit too.
That's gonna be nothing.
Burger as I predict.
Little still thick.
leah: Yeah.
I'm gonna come through that first.
I'll probably come out and scrub in my Maryland just to make myself feel better.
brian: Kind.
Worry.
What the hell that is?
leah: Yeah.
I don't know.
We're
brian: looking
leah: exactly
brian: blue.
Yeah, it probably is that, that would be like if I had to make a wave,
I was like, maybe.
But it also like under the colors, like really?
Here's another move.
We grab it
brian: gently and slide down just to a break.
It's fat.
It'll, it'll, it'll gradually disintegrate.
Don't vols it.
You know what I mean?
Don't grab so hard.
You're gonna vols.
Yeah.
Let it slide.
It should be sliding.
And you're gonna open and do it again.
Slide, slide, slide.
Not really fat, huh?
It almost looks a little thicker.
Like some sort of weird, like accessory.
leah: That's what I'm wondering.
Yeah, it's,
it's odd.
I dunno to do with that one.
Well, it looks like maybe like a weird accessory, like could be artery, like a posterior.
leah: Just trying to thin this out and see if we can see a structure in there versus just more fat.
brian: So your time bounced.
Good?
Yep.
leah: Good
brian: job.
I did see it that time.
I'm glad
leah: I do.
I hopefully could learn.
Okay.
Nice coaching.
Nice, nice, nice.
I'm just staying in that.
You a good athlete of some kind.
I can't remember really.
Um, yeah, not in college.
No.
What did you do before?
leah: Uh, volleyball and track.
Nice.
That was really good.
brian: Dissection.
leah: This is nothing here.
brian: It sure is nothing.
It might be a little like emphatic or something, right?
leah: Yeah.
I can burn it.
brian: Yeah.
I above that one just 'cause it looks like a structure of some kind before I switch.
I was gonna just see, see there's something back there.
Feel, I dunno.
I shouldn't make predictions.
Yes.
Engage the tips though.
You not pushing hard enough and do it.
leah: Oh shoot.
It is rolling off my tips.
So
posters moving like it's floppy so I dunno.
All right.
I'm gonna take that first one since it's bothering me and then we can see it better.
We're getting close.
We're doing it.
Go.
There we go.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see.
I gonna feel
It's starting to look like something more, isn't it?
leah: Yeah, it actually is.
Almost looks like a little vessel.
brian: It does, but it's entirely in the wrong direction.
I would've, if I had it bet, I would still say it's nothing but.
Like, it's not high enough confidence that we just blast it.
leah: Same.
brian: You know,
leah: I'm not gonna, I, how
brian: are we gonna dissect it?
It's like floppy and difficult.
It's not a bad idea.
leah: So it feels like there's a fat line there.
brian: I mean, I guess you can try and engage your chips, right?
I don't know what the hell that is.
Try and strip this down maybe.
Okay.
You know, see if we get better exposure to it goes to.
It's so floppy that I can't imagine it's a real structure.
Nice.
Perfect.
leah: Got it.
Almost like, is it something, I don't know.
brian: I don't know.
I like I told you, if I had the bed, I'd say no, but I kind of pulsing.
Yeah.
It looks like a, it's pulsing.
Do we think it's pulsing?
It's probably a posterior branch.
Okay.
It's definitely pulsing.
I just finally, yeah, I see it.
Yeah, right there.
So I, that little posse right there?
Yeah, right here.
Well,
leah: I lid That's
brian: wrong.
There you go.
I really engage that though.
But don't make big moves.
Get over overcharged.
I dunno.
I don't know.
Uh, can't.
I can't, I can't.
You
leah: wanna come take a feel or it
brian: better?
Yeah.
Keep working over more medial though.
Okay.
There's stuff there to do.
leah: Is there more stuff to do?
I dunno what else there is to do
because
leah: I think we can come across just
brian: grabbing
your gown.
Oh, thanks.
brian: Oh, maybe I can clear those.
It's okay
brian: scrubbed.
No, it's fine.
I'm just like Sandy, I don't want
leah: just coming around the backside of the duct, like hugging on it with my tips
and getting, you know, so much.
That way you can actually get around it.
Yeah, exactly.
I would love,
you know what, I would love to do
simulation using your kind that size.
Yeah.
Like I'm hugging around, um, the back
leah: and like kind of rolling off the back, feeling it, and
then trying to get that spread through that tissue behind it.
Yeah.
Nice.
There we go.
Kind of coming a little bit check and see, but how was the lady from yesterday doing?
Oh,
leah: she's doing okay.
She's still, they kept her intubated overnight.
She's under Nore at 0.08.
They're gonna ween her.
They weaned her sedation a bit and she was like following commands
her kidney function that, you know, it was at 6.6 when it peaked.
Yeah, it's down to four point.
Um, like three for creatinine, lactate's down to 2.1.
Nice.
Um, I,
it was definitely gonna be a bit for her to recover after all.
Oh yeah.
I mean, totally.
She was the sepsis besides the ballet.
That's,
brian: that's cool.
Yeah.
leah: I'm assuming you'll regrab Dr. George.
brian: Lemme just figure out what the hell that thing is.
That's weird, huh?
leah: Yeah.
Very weird.
Puls a tile, if you will back.
I'll take Marilyn.
You got it.
I'll just stand it there.
Marilyn, do you want that step out of the way?
brian: Me?
Yes.
I kind of like it was.
She's right.
Yeah, it's nice.
It's good stuff.
In fact, that was a learning point for me in this case, was that I should have suggested you get a step.
'cause I did notice your shoulder was really high.
Yeah, me too.
And she felt like it was wrong and immediately corrected.
You wouldn't know that.
So that was a failure on my part.
Well, I guess mine too.
That was my learning point for today.
One of them.
No, I was like, I was like awkward.
Like I wasn't sure if it was something that I was doing, you know what I mean?
Positioning wise of myself or not.
Nice.
It's a
leah: good angle for the um, clips.
brian: Okay, so that's nothing because I'm going from easier stuff to harder.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
That's something we can take
get there almost entirely off.
It's so floppy.
That's awesome.
It's got that.
It's got this handle thing.
Yeah.
Okay.
leah: Oh, nice.
Yeah.
Okay.
brian: Put that on.
Yeah, but I don't here to put that on stretch so I dissect a little more up.
Put that on stretch because I can't do anything.
Oh, nice.
leah: Yeah, that looks good.
You see that cat bad
hat?
That's
leah: nothing compared to me.
I think.
Oh, that's really pretty.
That's nice.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Dr. George's grip is a,
brian: it's a lot of, it's 10,000 little things, guys.
There's no mystery here.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's not rocket science.
It's not talent.
It isn't.
It's deliberate practice.
Folks.
Send the details for years, right?
That's all.
It's okay.
No secrets here.
Okay, so now we got that on a stretch, right?
Mm-hmm.
Which is my goal
leah: going directly into gallbladder.
It's where we're going into gallbladder.
Yeah.
So directly into gallbladder on back.
Okay.
Grab it like he did.
Probably not.
This is a weird little posterior branch, I guess.
leah: Yeah.
Thank you.
Okay.
Good to clip it and take it?
brian: Yeah.
leah: Okay.
I'll take the clip applier.
Yeah.
brian: Yeah, for sure.
I wanna take that posterior branch.
Pick that too, I think.
Okay.
I'll, if you think it's skeletonized,
leah: I, yeah.
I got my tines around it.
Okay.
While you're, but I'll show you.
brian: Okay.
You don't have to show me that.
I need to prove, just to know what you think.
Okay.
Now you get to redeem yourself.
Gonna stack, there we go.
Right.
Partial close.
Yes.
It's gonna be
leah: perfect.
brian: Partial, close.
leah: Make it in, maybe partial, close.
Slide it down
brian: so you kind of see it in your thing a little bit.
leah: Mm-hmm.
brian: Or feel it.
leah: I feel it.
brian: Perfect.
leah: Could have been a little better 'cause I started.
No, that's
brian: perfect.
Whatcha promise?
leah: Oh, no, I mean, I started, uh, I started pulling on it.
Oh.
So my tissue handling could have been better.
brian: All the way up.
All the way up.
Move yourself out to light.
And it's fire.
And you can see your tip there.
Yep.
Just do it.
You don't need to make it slow.
There.
The specimen side.
Scissors.
Thank you.
That's a straightaway.
leah: Okay.
When we talk about my velocity.
Yes.
brian: Yeah.
There was a little branch up in there and that's what that is.
You just cut through it, right?
Yep.
It was a weird little, I dunno, weird an anatomy here.
leah: I'm gonna just check and make sure I can get across this duct Well.
brian: See now it's when you see that, see that splays out a little bit.
Yeah.
At the bottom.
So I wonder, okay.
Yeah, exactly.
Where are we gonna go?
Is that the actual confluence?
Not sure.
leah: Hmm.
Do you use the big clip of wire or you use that same Uh, well, like the big white one, the
hemo lock is maybe what we want to do here because it's, yeah, I think we do want, okay.
Purple
brian: HELOC please.
Thank you.
leah: May I see another, um, grasper real quick saying something?
Yeah.
That also just felt like it,
brian: a good leadership
because I was thinking about how to work around with a clip that's not safe.
It's just better to do Right.
Thing
done
leah: there.
So smart.
Yeah.
Well, I knew I had a bad angle and I didn't like my grab.
brian: Yeah.
So you see how it's slinging out a little bit where the co I think confluence is Yep.
Right there.
So you're gonna say half a millimeter above that.
Okay.
Please.
Oh, I can see now where like that narrowing is and then there's that And that's the confluence over there.
Yeah, exactly right.
It could be, could be.
But this is the narrowing hearing.
You're gonna wanna go this way.
That's, that's right.
Exactly.
brian: And not that it is, that it could be.
Okay.
I was doing probability with my daughter last night and I was
talking about how reality is all about, like, you don't know, am I
leah: pushing a hair more with your Yep.
Yeah.
Perfect.
brian: Probabilistic reasoning.
So there's zero tolerance for error there, so we just err on the side of caution.
Perfect.
Kind of like how the physicists and their, uh, like what we were talking about.
Yeah.
brian: There's no six Sigma here.
We don't get that usually.
Um,
probability for fun or does she have homework?
brian: Not for fun.
Uh, so I homeschooled her last year.
I took her year off.
I homeschooled her.
The only chapter we didn't do in our geometry was, this doesn't make any sense probability.
And so the school was mad at me 'cause I had skipped it.
So I, we waited for the summer.
So we have nice
leah: cool little anatomy with that posterior branch.
brian: Do what?
leah: The anatomy with the little posterior branch.
It's nice to see.
Oh.
Always scared.
I'm gonna get burned by one of those.
I dig in back there.
brian: It's good to see that.
I supposed to do
leah: clip clip.
Cut off the Foss.
brian: Yeah.
Thank God she's back from public school.
God bless.
Teachers.
You did
homeschooling for one year?
brian: Yeah, I took a year off and we lived in an rv.
Oh yeah.
So we had to homeschool.
We did a terrible job.
Job.
I did a drill job on everything but geometry.
I filled it with geometry.
Where'd you guys travel?
Mostly out last we were climbing.
So nice.
Appreciate teachers.
brian: Yeah.
I mean, I've always appreciated teachers, but I really appreciate It's really hard.
You
good?
Yeah, no, I was gonna say, I never truly came to appreciate our, like some of the stats programs.
All I had to do was put the data and I didn't have to calculate any of those.
Like, you know what I mean?
brian: You're like, why did I need to know Data error.
No, I mean it's like important to know it, but I'm like, I don't want to have to like, you know what I mean?
Like having to calculate all that stuff.
I just remember with like genetics and everything, how we were doing that.
Oh, it was painful.
brian: One of my very close friends is doing his PhD right now.
He's taking a very high level stats.
He's like God's gift to me when I'm doing research.
It's cool.
A
very good biostatistic biostatistician work for weight and gold.
leah: That's for sure.
brian: I, so I did a master's education, but it was really a master's in Stats for education.
So I really love stats.
leah: Little hooky part, you know, goes in the back.
Mm-hmm.
So I always fix that before I get in so I don't have to puts around.
brian: Okay.
Perfectly loaded.
Thank you.
leah: Okay.
Wanna see the back?
All right.
Now let's look to the confluence.
Nice.
I think about right there.
Yeah.
brian: I think that's great.
Good job.
Those are lovely, aren't they?
leah: I like 'em a lot.
I just, I'll think another piece.
Secure,
especially with me too.
I feel very secure.
This is actually, she had dilated ducts and
leah: she has that stint like she needs She could pressure.
Exactly.
Yeah.
This is great.
I don't wanna sit.
Let's put four of them on.
I can't tell if you're serious or kidding.
Not serious.
Okay.
Putting, like, you lined up your clip before you went in.
leah: Yeah.
I like to go in and get it on the back.
brian: Oh, she switched it.
So the angle's different.
Mm-hmm.
So she had the backside on the, what is now the, the tearing towards you.
Yeah.
You gotta come, come out.
Because what changed now is you have it facing down.
Mm-hmm.
You want the knob behind your duct, right?
Yep.
But now you have it facing down and your angle across the duct is not the same.
Okay.
Before she loaded, I'm gonna come fully out.
Come out and have it reloaded.
Okay.
So we're gonna want to, so this one's here.
Yeah.
So knob on that side.
leah: Thanks.
And Dr. George, are you gonna take off the fossa?
brian: Yeah, I'll do that if you don't mind.
Yeah, yeah.
Course.
Because it'll be done.
leah: Just figured I'd clarify.
brian: Perfect.
Uh, not, not perfect.
We'll try it.
I think it's wrong.
You had it scooped up with the knob behind you, right?
Mm-hmm.
The first time.
Yep.
Yeah, I think, lemme see.
Yeah.
So it's gotta be the exact opposite.
So scooped up.
It's a on that side.
Okay.
I think it's where the,
on that side.
Thankfully
leah: my PhD wish we had programs at the.
Way.
Can we just turn it this way?
Sure.
brian: No, because the angle, here's why.
See the angle, it's 30 degrees.
If you turn it there, it's 30 degrees that way it's a 60 degree angle difference
and it actually messes us up for getting up parallel and perfectly placed.
So this is our last chance.
Sure.
Hungry.
Did I eat?
Yeah, I did.
We thought that last time.
I even eat too, but I feel like I've been hungry as a rotation.
I don't know if it's because I'm running around more
leah: can wake all day.
brian: I could be wrong sometimes we're not out.
I'm excited though.
Our tomato plans finally.
How's it looking?
We're
leah: good.
Okay.
brian: So next one we'll be facing that way and really shot.
Really?
All righty.
Oh, that makes her face Is this, that's our, that's our mnemonic.
Okay.
leah: Okay.
I think I'm right on top.
Pushed across.
I always try to feel like I'm really engaging all the way across.
That's true.
Sweet.
I'll take one more Vore.
Thank you.
There's a little bit of schmutz there, so I'm gonna try to like slide it up.
Yeah, we'll see.
It's here for you.
leah: Um, oh, sorry.
And then you mind pushing up a little bit.
Kad over the Interesting.
Yeah.
Can you read, um, it's like twisting.
I, I think you're pushing to the Yeah, exactly.
That's better.
That's nice.
Actually, maybe that made it worse.
brian: And you can always use a clip player here if you need to.
Okay, sure.
leah: Okay.
brian: Because you can not get it all the way around and it's specimen, it doesn't matter.
leah: Right.
I'm gonna just see my posterior time, which I do not see.
brian: Just use a clip.
leah: Sorry.
brian: Okay.
I was gonna say just use a clip.
Yeah.
leah: No, I don't like that.
I don't, you can't feel it
brian: because your duct flow's not very long, you know?
Yeah.
If you are able to do it, you're gonna be really close.
I'd rather have more duct in a shitty specimen closure, I think.
leah: Okay.
brian: Or you could skeletonize more, but that's not a good use of time.
So just take a clip of fire, fire above where you are right now.
leah: So fire this higher.
brian: A clip of fire.
Higher.
Yeah.
Follow me?
leah: No.
brian: Okay.
So take this out and, oh, okay.
Okay.
brian: Thank you.
I was like, he's like, how does she not get this?
I don't know how to say it.
This, she's can't slow, can.
No, no, no.
Kat, I would not communicating clearly.
I'll slide up though.
Don't get all the way across.
It doesn't matter.
Slide up.
Give yourself room.
Okay.
brian: Keep going.
Slide, slide, slide.
There you go.
Now flip it.
Okay.
Good enough.
leah: Ah, okay.
Okay.
We come back.
You can just a hair.
Yeah, you're good.
Scissors.
leah: Thank you.
And I'll give us a lot of length.
Cut up high.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I just don't
brian: wanna have any slippage.
leah: All right, let's pop on in there.
brian: Oh, these hemo locks are really good.
No, no stone's in there.
Shit.
No.
I saw you milked earlier.
Yeah, but I'm sad to see.
leah: Okay, good.
This still come across?
brian: Yeah, we're gonna need it.
Can you get suction up for us please?
Okay.
Absolutely
leah: rats.
Yeah, I milked it too.
I know you did.
Yeah, I saw.
brian: Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, while you were palpating, you were milking.
leah: Yeah,
brian: it's all good.
leah: It didn't feel super stony to be totally honest.
brian: I don't know that we need irrigation, actually.
Just inception.
Okay.
Yeah, we need that.
Yeah, but we maybe, well, I'll just leave
it, sit there for just a few off.
brian: I mean, you know, sir, we never change her mind.
Right?
Come.
leah: Hope she doesn't have a drop stone.
What?
Hope she doesn't have a dropped.
brian: We also never lie about time because she has the,
leah: she already has the stricture.
Yesterday, I think I said maybe she should get an ERCP after Ask Dr. George or some, Hey,
Dr. George, since she has a stricture already, we don't know if she has a drop stone.
Should we just keep her and like get LFTs and, or would you just let her go home and She's got a stent?
She does have a stent for her to obstruct.
She still has.
Okay.
So because her, her stent has, has occluded once.
brian: So, I mean, I don't how long.
Okay.
No, I wouldn't keep it.
leah: Do you want me to try to,
brian: uh, suck up the stone if you Oh, do you have a 10 milliliter, um, uh, suction tip catheter.
Gotcha.
We don't have a big one.
I can go get one.
Oh, it's
brian: not in the set?
No.
brian: Let's see.
We'll see if this sucks it up.
It might.
How about I wander that way?
So that sounds
brian: like a great idea.
Okay.
Your suction is on it.
Go get that.
Thanks.
leah: All right.
I got that little guy out.
It's pretty good.
All right.
Good job.
brian: Because I was just avoiding drop stone.
Yeah, I I've done that one too.
Had to reoperate on someone.
A year later.
leah: A year later.
Gracious.
brian: Well, yeah, 'cause it had an un resolving abscess.
Yeah.
And I finally just, just like dug it out.
It was really ugly.
leah: I could probably bo be that, but
brian: That's great.
Good job.
leah: Thank you.
This is really nice.
leah: Nice.
I feel like when it comes off the too nicely, it's like oddly satisfying, you know?
Oh yeah.
brian: Edge mean
like when you're coming.
Fsa.
The fsa, I meant, sorry.
It just very, like, when it just comes right off and it just, and like,
brian: come
in
Cauter
brian: down here.
leah: Thank you.
Okay.
Come up.
brian: That grabs not good.
Right?
See, I don't have enough tension.
I come.
Yeah.
Could you come underneath so I can do as much as I possibly can?
leah: Yep.
brian: While I have what I have, but I'm gonna run out a minute here very quickly.
It's awkward, it's slow.
Yeah.
Speaking velocity and I'm just like back.
Good job.
Every time I move, you want to avoid me, like, be afraid because I'm gonna, you,
leah: you're doing great, Dagan.
I don't think it's
brian: so nice.
This is a good, so the move, yeah.
Heel up grab under wide.
Okay.
Lift
leah: that
brian: puppy
leah: up
brian: in that angle.
That's not a very good grab.
And then I turn my thing on parallel, but it's not quite, not like that, but like that, not
like that, but like that so that the heel's sliding off and I barely touch my instrument.
Okay.
Too far over as part of it.
Oh, nice, nice.
That's not a great grab I take anyway.
brian: Okay.
Anyways, that's how you keep your hook and get it out without perforating the gall
training.
Great tension over there.
Can't really
brian: see good.
Oh, there's some good tension.
Yeah.
Nice.
Come across.
That's yellow there.
That means it'd,
it's kind of a weird angle.
Usually on that side more, but I can't get there very easily, so I'm just avoiding it.
Tension there.
I have tension there, but I'm gonna release it.
Come in so I can cook this and it doesn't come apart anyway, so not my idea.
Now there's a vessel there, so I'm gonna cook right there.
It's gonna pull harder
here
still.
brian: Great tension there.
Okay, come back.
Your left hand.
Can you?
That's the problem actually, I didn't realize your left hand is pulling too far to the patient's left.
There you go.
That'll help me a lot.
Thank you.
Come in the camera.
Can you.
Okay.
There we go.
Come in.
leah: Good tension there.
brian: I don't like cooking just happened, so I did not have enough tension in my plane.
There's quite here.
Flip there Some planes there.
leah: Could cat regrab to help you or no?
No.
Okay.
brian: I don't think so.
It's just, I mean, yes, but it's not worth the time.
Okay.
I'll adjust.
She'll eventually pull towards her over the right patient's.
Right.
Even more right now.
Patient's, right?
Yep.
Patient's right.
Good.
Thanks.
Stop there.
leah: Oh, nice.
Yeah.
brian: How's that?
Oh, you're pulling to our just a cap too.
It's not your fault.
Yeah, it's
okay.
I understand My planes right now.
Okay.
I gotta grab closer.
Every time I fail, I grab closer
brian: out.
Out.
See, I can't get a good grab.
Why can't I get a good grab?
I wanna go underneath, but it's not really working.
Why not Kat come towards you a little bit more and lower?
Don't put a lot of tension on it.
Just rotate.
Okay.
Nice.
That's great.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Nice.
Let's try this effort.
Come on in through the haze.
brian: It's
on the run here.
Oh
leah: yeah.
brian: Pull straight up.
Now
you guys could all this, it would just take a little, it would take us a little.
leah: No problem.
Okay,
leah: come.
Woo, let's go.
I don't
brian: let go.
leah: Nice
brian: breakfast.
Mm-hmm.
leah: Sorry.
brian: Done, please.
Nice.
leah: Sometimes the jaws get locked on that tissue, so you have to turn that
brian: up and shake
leah: it up.
Shake it,
brian: hook them all the way.
Shake.
leah: Nice.
Good job.
Kelly, please.
Kelly,
just for a sec.
Maybe vent again.
What?
Vent again?
brian: We were getting low.
Keep vent again?
Yeah.
Forever.
leah: Oh, forever.
brian: Come in.
So you didn't spill any bm, so I won't, I won't irrigate rather just little bit.
leah: Okay.
Look at that duct.
Nice
one.
leah: Great clips look great static.
Another use this.
brian: Okay.
Put that over there.
Color, please.
Mm-hmm.
leah: Do you have a Ray Tech?
brian: Huh?
leah: Oh, I was asking for Ray Tech.
Thank you.
brian: Specimen?
Mm-hmm.
Carter Thompson please.
leah: You grab a hunter.
Okay.
brian: I usually use, oh my bad.
It's okay.
Grab it.
leah: Oh, you did tell me that yesterday.
brian: More degrees of freedom because of the angle.
Okay, gotcha.
Turn your, your instrument so you can see both times next time.
Make it easier on you.
Okay.
Ready for your,
you happen.
leah: Have a gall bladder for permanent snap on this side.
You have Snap please.
Snap right on this one.
No, you're good.
And then do you have that Maryland?
Yeah.
Just in case
she's keeping it.
brian: It's bloody strange.
Bloody, bloody
nice.
Sure did better.
leah: Just make sure he gets the right end.
Yeah.
Nice.
brian: There's a needle.
Mm-hmm.
leah: No, let's just have blood there.
brian: Sorry to come at you with that.
Little aggressively.
Okay.
We don't tie it up yet because it's insulated, but I wanna make sure that we at least are sealed.
Adequate for reuse.
Right?
Feels fine.
Maybe I'll stop the bleeding too.
Okay, let's take out these ports.
You show me this port, please.
This one.
leah: Nice.
Good job.
brian: This one, we go back and forth between the two.
Looking for bleeding,
great plate and camera before it hits the fall or not Before all the way out it back in.
I want see those ports and then when it comes up to you, you're gonna have to come out
leah: and then just leave that in there.
Let it all the gas come out.
That
brian: patient please.
Overhead.
Lights up.
Please House for the camera.
Mm-hmm.
leah: And then we have the tip if you'd like to change tips.
I am ready for a gall.